<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-09T10:30:14-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">capncapes.github.io</title><subtitle>A blog site built with Jekyll consisting of two blogs, a feed of book reviews, and other content pages.</subtitle><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to create a Google account without Gmail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to create a Google account without Gmail" /><published>2022-11-03T08:14:59-04:00</published><updated>2022-11-03T08:14:59-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can have a Google account without a Gmail address? With so many products and services, millions of people use Google. But what if you like your existing email address? You can create a Google account without Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially useful when using Google’s business services, like Search Console, Google Ads, Google Analytics, etc. It’s a really nice way to compartmentalize your personal and work accounts and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Google services, like Google Ads, allow administrators to restrict users to those with specific email domains, such as those of your business. For Ads, this is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/2375456?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;font-bold&quot;&gt;Allowed Domains&lt;/a&gt;. But you must also have a Google account to use these products, which is exactly how I ended up creating my new non-Gmail account this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://accounts.google.com/SignUpWithoutGmail&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accounts.google.com/SignUpWithoutGmail&lt;/a&gt; to get started. Fill out the form (pictured below) using the email address that you want to use when signing into your new Google account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/create-your-google-account.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/create-your-google-account.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Create your Google account without Gmail&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;, update your new account with additional information, like your gender and birthdate. Next, verify that you’re human by completing the CAPTCHA. Agree to Google’s Terms of Service and Privacy Policy by checking the corresponding box. Now click &lt;strong&gt;Next step&lt;/strong&gt; to submit the form and create your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your Google account created, you will now need to confirm that you own the email address provided. Go to your email inbox and look for an email from Google. Click the link inside to confirm your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can sign into your new Google account, and the email address username is your non-Gmail address!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="Google" /><summary type="html">Did you know that you can have a Google account without a Gmail address? With so many products and services, millions of people use Google. But what if you like your existing email address? You can create a Google account without Gmail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remove .DS_Store with Git</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remove .DS_Store with Git" /><published>2022-06-25T23:14:39-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-25T23:14:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store">&lt;p&gt;Every developer with a Mac computer has encountered the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; file in their Git code. If you don’t know what it is, this file could be alarming. Don’t worry; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; is harmless. But it can be annoying when it shows up in every folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-ds_store-file&quot;&gt;What is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; file?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; is a hidden metadata file exclusive to Mac computers, though you could possibly come across it on a Windows PC that is sharing project code with a Mac. The file simply contains information specific to the folder it’s in: folder color, icon size, window size, file order, etc. The file is created the first time you select any View Options for a folder, but it’s hidden using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; prefix. However, you can see it in the terminal using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; command. And of course, it also shows up in Git repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-remove-ds_store-files-from-a-git-repository&quot;&gt;How to remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files from a Git repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove (and prevent) &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from your project code, I recommend first checking out a new branch with the following command: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git checkout -b [BRANCH-NAME]&lt;/code&gt;. Then make sure you’re in the root of your project folder so that your changes will affect the whole project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remove-ds_store&quot;&gt;Remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the following terminal command to find all previously committed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files and remove them from your project. If &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git rm&lt;/code&gt; makes you uneasy, you can perform a dry run to check the files that would be removed, without actually removing anything. To do this, add either &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--dry-run&lt;/code&gt; as a flag following &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt;, like this: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;... git rm -n --ignore-unmatch&lt;/code&gt;. Once you’ve seen what will be removed, repeat the full command without the flag to remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot; data-lang=&quot;console&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;find . -name .DS_Store -print0 | xargs -0 git rm --ignore-unmatch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;add-to-gitignore&quot;&gt;Add to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from entering your project’s code again, add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**/.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file. If it does not exist, create the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of your project folder and add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**/.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; on its own line. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; part of the command tells Git that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files should be ignored in every folder of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commit-changes&quot;&gt;Commit changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commit your changes and push them to your remote repository. If you review the changes made in your version control host, you’ll notice that the updates remove all the instances of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;, along with adding that line to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="web development" /><category term="Git" /><summary type="html">Every developer with a Mac computer has encountered the .DS_Store file in their Git code. If you don’t know what it is, this file could be alarming. Don’t worry; .DS_Store is harmless. But it can be annoying when it shows up in every folder.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is eternal life: know your God</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is eternal life: know your God" /><published>2022-05-26T11:39:31-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T11:39:31-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life">&lt;p&gt;“Is this real life?” &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/txqiwrbYGrs&quot;&gt;David After Dentist&lt;/a&gt; is a hilarious viral video of a 7-year old boy fresh out of a dental procedure who is clearly still feeling the effects of nitrous oxide, or laughing gas. David’s father assures him that, yes, this is real life. But for Christians, this is also eternal life. We’re living in it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eternal-life-is-knowing-god&quot;&gt;Eternal life is knowing God&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In John 17, Jesus defines eternal life as knowing God:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus spoke these things, looked up to heaven, and said, “Father, the hour has come. Glorify your Son so that the Son may glorify you, &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; since you gave him authority over all people, so that he may give eternal life to everyone you have given him. &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; This is eternal life: that they may know you, the only true God, and the one you have sent—Jesus Christ. &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I have glorified you on the earth by completing the work you gave me to do. &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Now, Father, glorify me in your presence with that glory I had with you before the world existed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 17:1–5, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Christian Standard Bible&quot;&gt;CSB&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This passage is the beginning of the longest recorded prayer of Jesus, and it’s filled with love for his disciples—all of us throughout history. As Gary M. Burge notes, &lt;q&gt;John 17 gives us a glimpse into the heart of Jesus unlike any other chapter in the four Gospels.&lt;/q&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The NIV Application Commentary: John&lt;/em&gt;) Dane Ortlund takes it further in his book, &lt;a href=&quot;/book-reviews/gentle-and-lowly&quot; class=&quot;italic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gentle and Lowly&lt;/a&gt;, when he describes Christ’s bottomless well of grace: &lt;q&gt;Jesus Christ is comforted when you draw from the riches of his atoning work, because his own body is getting healed.&lt;/q&gt; Jesus desires for his people to not only be with him eternally, but to come to him now, in this age, for grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack in just these five verses, but one phrase that is often overlooked is, “This is eternal life: that they may know you” (v. 3). Louis Berkhof describes the nature of eternal life in his major theological treatise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The reward of the righteous is described as eternal life, that is, not merely an endless life, but life in all its fulness, without any of the imperfections and disturbances of the present, Matt. 25:46; Rom. 2:7. The fulness of this life is enjoyed in communion with God, which is really the essence of eternal life, Rev. 21:3. They will see God in Jesus Christ face to face, will find full satisfaction in Him, will rejoice in Him, and will glorify Him.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Louis Berkhof, Systematic Theology&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eternal life is not simply living forever, nor does it begin once the faithful believer dies. The gift of eternal life is complete and everlasting union with the fullness of God in Jesus Christ, face to face. Even better, it begins in this life. If eternal life, as defined by Christ himself, is to know God, then those of us who know God are experiencing it now. Eternal life for the Christian bleeds backward into time. Just as a door can be opened to let in the sunshine while a person is still inside, so too, can the Christian experience the warmth of the Son in this present life. And how much better to finally pass through that open door into the fresh air of God’s full glory? (Philippians 1:12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;obstacles-to-experiencing-eternal-life-now&quot;&gt;Obstacles to experiencing eternal life now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many obstacles to experiencing the warmth of Jesus in this present life. To continue with the open door analogy, there’s a lot happening in this room. Life gets busy and distracting. Our bodies and minds are imperfect, plaguing us with physical and mental sicknesses. Anxiety, depression, cancer, eating disorders, insomnia. Evil abounds, striving always to turn our eyes and hearts away from Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These “imperfections and disturbances,” as Berkhof calls them, can be seriously heavy burdens. It would be dismissive to suggest that the person struggling with depression simply have more faith, though. God chooses to work primarily through his creation, and we’re not meant to live the Christian life alone. &lt;q cite=&quot;Galatians 6:2, CSB&quot;&gt;Carry one another’s burdens,&lt;/q&gt; (Galatians 6:2, CSB) and allow others to carry yours. Seek professional help, if needed, to manage the things that might prevent you from experiencing the Son of God presently. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a weak faith that treats &lt;em&gt;fill-in-the-blank&lt;/em&gt; with health providers, prescribed medication, or licensed therapists.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;look-to-the-second-coming&quot;&gt;Look to the second coming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Christians, our hope is found in Jesus and his second coming to restore all things to perfection. We are told to watch and pray in anticipation of the second coming of Christ, &lt;q cite=&quot;Jude 21, CSB&quot;&gt;waiting expectantly for the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ for eternal life.&lt;/q&gt; (Jude 21, CSB)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="eternal life" /><category term="eschatology" /><category term="gospels" /><summary type="html">“Is this real life?” David After Dentist is a hilarious viral video of a 7-year old boy fresh out of a dental procedure who is clearly still feeling the effects of nitrous oxide, or laughing gas. David’s father assures him that, yes, this is real life. But for Christians, this is also eternal life. We’re living in it now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using CSS counters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/using-css-counters" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using CSS counters" /><published>2021-11-04T14:03:01-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-04T14:03:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/using-css-counters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/using-css-counters">&lt;p&gt;CSS. Developers tend to either love it or hate it—sometimes depending on the day. Well, here’s a reason to love it: CSS counters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we can simply use an ordered list to count items on a web page, but that doesn’t always fit semantically. And CSS counters are a bit more flexible than boring old lists, in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-use-css-counters&quot;&gt;How to use CSS counters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using CSS counters, there are four properties and one function we can work with: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter()&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;counter-reset&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/code&gt; property to create our counter on the parent element of the items we wish to count. The property can accept two values: a counter’s name and a number from which to increment. The number value is optional and defaults to 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The increment number can be a little confusing because the value provided is the starting point, so the first counted item will display the next incremented value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Same result as above */&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Begin at 4 */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/code&gt; can also reset an existing counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;counter-increment&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/code&gt; property defines the increment on the specified counter. This property can accept one or two values: either the name of a counter to increment or the name of a counter plus a number specifying the increment amount. If only the name of a counter is provided, the default increment of 1 is used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* 1, 2, 3, 4... */&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Same result as above */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* 3, 6, 9, 12... */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;counter-set&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have defined our counters and their increments, we can &lt;em&gt;set&lt;/em&gt; a starting point. That’s where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt; comes in. This property accepts a counter name and the starting value of the counter. The element it’s used on will be the starting point for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt; value. Leaving the starting value out makes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt; default to 0. In cases where you might have multiple counters on an element, you can use multiple name-value pairs. You can also set &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt; to none to cancel a less specific &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/code&gt; style rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: We could leave out this property to let the counting start at the default of 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
24
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;:first-of-type::before&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Start at 0 */&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Start at 300 */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.nth-of-type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;::before&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;py&quot;&gt;counter-set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* 1, 2, -2, -1, 0, 1, 2, 3... */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;counter&quot;&gt;counter()&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter()&lt;/code&gt; function returns a string representing the value of the specified counter. This is how our counter will be displayed visually. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter()&lt;/code&gt; function is generally used with pseudo-elements and the content property, but it could theoretically be used anywhere a string value is accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To display our counter, we need to provide the counter name to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;counter()&lt;/code&gt; function. The function accepts a second argument to define the style. Any valid &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/list-style-type&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;list-style-type&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; value is also valid here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8
9
10
11
12
13
14
15
16
17
18
19
20
21
22
23
24
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#one&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;::before&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;counter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;counter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;myCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;decimal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* Same result as above */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-reset&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;counter-increment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#two&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.child&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;::before&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;counter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;yourCounter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;lower-alpha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;defining-custom-css-counters&quot;&gt;Defining custom CSS counters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the standard list-style-type values aren’t sufficient, you could define your own custom counter style with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/@counter-style&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@counter-style&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; CSS at-rule. From the MDN Web Docs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The initial version of CSS defined a set of useful counter styles. However, although more styles were added to this set of predefined styles over the years, this system proved too restrictive to fulfill the needs of worldwide typography. The @counter-style at-rule addresses this shortcoming in an open-ended manner, by allowing authors to define their own counter styles when the pre-defined styles aren’t fitting their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t get into &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@counter-style&lt;/code&gt; this time, but check out the tutorial on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quackit.com/css/at-rules/css_counter-style_at-rule.cfm&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@counter-style&lt;/code&gt; CSS at-rule&lt;/a&gt; over at Quackit. To see the rest of the CSS counter tools in action, take a look at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/collection/gYzzQv&quot;&gt;Codepen collection about CSS counters&lt;/a&gt;, and watch this &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/XFXVJBzsMCA&quot;&gt;video tutorial by Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt; about ordered lists and CSS counters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using CSS counters is pretty easy once you understand the the few properties involved. I prefer CSS counters when the task is about styling. If you need proper list markup, this isn’t the method to use. (You’re probably looking for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/html-list-how-to-use-bullet-points-ordered-and-unordered-lists/&quot;&gt;HTML lists&lt;/a&gt;.) Nevertheless, there’s a lot you can do with only a handful of CSS.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="web development" /><category term="CSS" /><summary type="html">CSS. Developers tend to either love it or hate it—sometimes depending on the day. Well, here’s a reason to love it: CSS counters.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why was John the Baptist mistaken for Elijah?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2021/john-the-baptist-mistaken-for-elijah" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why was John the Baptist mistaken for Elijah?" /><published>2021-09-17T01:11:10-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T01:11:10-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2021/john-the-baptist-mistaken-for-elijah</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2021/john-the-baptist-mistaken-for-elijah">&lt;p&gt;Do you ever wonder about John the Baptist? Why did he dress in camel’s hair? What made him decide to live in the wilderness? Why was he mistaken for the prophet Elijah? The gospels make it clear that John was the appointed messenger to prepare the way for Jesus Christ. But why was his life so strange? It turns out, he was simply committing to his God-given mission, and he didn’t want anyone to miss the Messiah when he arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;god-chose-john-the-baptist&quot;&gt;God chose John the Baptist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John the Baptist was chosen by God to prepare the people for the ministry of Jesus. His purpose was clear, as the apostle John recorded in his gospel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; There was a man sent from God, whose name was John. &lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; He came as a witness, to bear witness about the light, that all might believe through him. &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; He was not the light, but came to bear witness about the light.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 1:6–8 (&lt;abbr title=&quot;English Standard Version&quot;&gt;ESV&lt;/abbr&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prophet Isaiah received a message from God about John in Isaiah 40:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A voice cries:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;q&gt;In the wilderness prepare the way of the Lord; make straight in the desert a highway for our God.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;q&gt;Every valley shall be lifted up, and every mountain and hill be made low; the uneven ground shall become level, and the rough places a plain.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;q&gt;And the glory of the Lord shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see it together, for the mouth of the Lord has spoken.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Isaiah 40:3–5, ESV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All four gospels reference this passage from Isaiah (Matthew 3:3, Mark 1:3, Luke 3:1–6, John 1:23).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John was transparent about who he was, but some people thought he was the Christ (Luke 3:15). He responded to these claims with the famous words comparing his own baptism of water to baptism by Jesus with the Holy Spirit and fire (Matthew 3:11, Luke 3:16, John 1:33). He continually used his ministry to point to Jesus. John was so passionate about preparing people for Jesus that his own disciples left him to follow the Master once he showed up. John himself pointed Jesus out to them (John 1:35–37).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-elijah&quot;&gt;Why Elijah?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John the Baptist was also mistaken for Elijah the Tishbite (John 1:21). But why Elijah? Whenever we read Scripture, it’s important to understand the context. John preached to a Jewish culture, and Jewish people knew the Scriptures, which for them was what we call the Old Testament. In the first chapter of 2 Kings, King Ahaziah recognized the prophet Elijah simply by a description of his clothing: &lt;q&gt;a garment of hair, with a belt of leather about his waist.&lt;/q&gt; (2 Kings 1:8, ESV) Elijah was well-known for his appearance, and John’s audience likely would have understood the reference, though many people still failed to see John the Baptist for who he was during his ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John the Baptist dressed in the same unique way as Elijah the Tishbite because he knew his calling: to “go before [Jesus] in the spirit and power of Elijah, to turn the hearts” (Luke 1:17, ESV) of God’s people back to Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last words from God before the birth of Jesus are recorded in Malachi 4:5–6, declaring that God will send Elijah the prophet to “turn the hearts” of His people. (It’s interesting that he’s referred to as &lt;em&gt;the prophet&lt;/em&gt; here rather than &lt;em&gt;the Tishbite&lt;/em&gt;, suggesting that the actual person of Elijah was not prophesied to prepare the way for Jesus.) These words are echoed by an angel in Luke 1:16–17 when John’s father, Zechariah, receives the news that he will have a son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John knew the calling on his life (Luke 1:67–79) and did everything he could to ensure that people didn’t miss who he was, and more importantly, who Jesus is. Malachi prophesied that God would send Elijah to prepare the way of the Lord, then 400 years later the angel Gabriel told Zechariah that his son would fulfill this prophecy. On either side of the intertestamental period between the Old and New Testaments is John the Baptist—first, his prophecy, then his appearance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it isn’t already clear who John the Baptist was, consider Jesus’ words to Peter, James, and John following His transfiguration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; And as they were coming down the mountain, Jesus commanded them, &lt;q&gt;Tell no one the vision, until the Son of Man is raised from the dead.&lt;/q&gt; &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; And the disciples asked him, &lt;q&gt;Then why do the scribes say that first Elijah must come?&lt;/q&gt; &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; He answered, &lt;q&gt;Elijah does come, and he will restore all things. &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt; But I tell you that Elijah has already come, and they did not recognize him, but did to him whatever they pleased. So also the Son of Man will certainly suffer at their hands.&lt;/q&gt; &lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; Then the disciples understood that he was speaking to them of John the Baptist.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 17:9–13, ESV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;embrace-your-calling&quot;&gt;Embrace your calling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The life of John the Baptist is a great example of what God can accomplish through someone who embraces his or her calling. John lived in the wilderness (Luke 1:80) and dressed like Elijah the Tishbite because he knew that Isaiah and Malachi prophesied that he would prepare the people for “the Lamb of God, who takes away the sin of the world!” (John 1:29, ESV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you and I willing to go to such lengths for the sake of God’s mission?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="Elijah" /><category term="John the Baptist" /><summary type="html">Do you ever wonder about John the Baptist? Why did he dress in camel’s hair? What made him decide to live in the wilderness? Why was he mistaken for the prophet Elijah? The gospels make it clear that John was the appointed messenger to prepare the way for Jesus Christ. But why was his life so strange? It turns out, he was simply committing to his God-given mission, and he didn’t want anyone to miss the Messiah when he arrived.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The average color of the universe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/average-color-universe" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The average color of the universe" /><published>2021-08-24T11:32:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-08-24T11:32:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/average-color-universe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2021/average-color-universe">&lt;p&gt;In 2002, Ivan Baldry and Karl Glazebrook, professors from the U.K. and Australia, respectively, co-led a research study to measure the light emitted from tens of thousands of galaxies and developed a single spectrum of light to represent the entire universe. You can read about their research at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livescience.com/average-color-of-universe.html&quot;&gt;Live Science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that spectrum, the team also computed the average color of the universe: “a beige shade not too far off from white” called cosmic latte. Other suggestions by the research team included cappuccino cosmico, primordial clam chowder, and Big Bang beige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average color of the universe being beige may sound boring, but it makes sense. Combining all the wavelengths of visible light results in the color white, and the cosmic spectrum contains many different wavelengths. The research team also adjusted the colors in their spectrum to account for redshift, which causes light to appear more red as it stretches across space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cosmic latte may not be the flashiest color, but wouldn’t it be neat to use the average color of the universe in your next web or design project? Here are the color codes for cosmic latte:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;thead&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;Hex&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;RGB&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th&gt;HSL&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/thead&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td data-table-heading=&quot;Hex&quot;&gt;#FFF8E7&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td data-table-heading=&quot;RGB&quot;&gt;rgb(255, 248, 231)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td data-table-heading=&quot;HSL&quot;&gt;hsl(43, 100%, 95%)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="graphic design" /><summary type="html">In 2002, Ivan Baldry and Karl Glazebrook, professors from the U.K. and Australia, respectively, co-led a research study to measure the light emitted from tens of thousands of galaxies and developed a single spectrum of light to represent the entire universe. You can read about their research at Live Science.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SEO terms explained</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2020/seo-terms-explained" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SEO terms explained" /><published>2020-04-26T14:25:20-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T14:25:20-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2020/seo-terms-explained</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2020/seo-terms-explained">&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization (SEO) can be very complicated, and even small changes to search engines’ algorithms can cause panic in the marketing community. There’s an entire SEO industry of professionals who spend 100% of their time optimizing websites for clients. But not everyone can afford to hire an SEO agency, so it’s helpful to have SEO terms explained in plain English for those of us who plan to get our hands dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re asking yourself, &lt;a href=&quot;2018-09-15-what-is-seo.md&quot;&gt;“What is SEO?”&lt;/a&gt; check out my article answering that very question. It’s important to understand what search engine optimization is and how to use that knowledge. Essentially, it boils down to this: SEO is the practice of making strategic and technical changes to a web page in order to position it to rank on search engine results pages (SERP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;seo-terms-explained&quot;&gt;SEO Terms Explained&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a general understanding of search engine optimization, let’s see some SEO terms explained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alt-attribute&quot;&gt;Alt Attribute&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alt attribute is used within the  tag to define an image in words. This is used by search engines to determine what a picture is in order to provide relevant search results to a user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attribute also helps humans. When a browser can’t load an image for some reason, it will display the alt text in its place. If the text is descriptive enough, the person can get a sense of what the image should be. Alt text is also used by screen readers to describe images to visually impaired users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alt attribute is a great place to put a keyword that you want to rank for. It should still describe the picture, so using relevant pictures is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engines like web pages with pictures because they’re typically more engaging to users, and it’s worth the effort to add alt attributes to your pictures. If a page contains an image without an alt attribute, the search engine doesn’t know what that picture represents. The page is then likely to rank worse because there’s a mysterious image that might not be relevant to a user’s search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anchor-text&quot;&gt;Anchor Text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In HTML, an anchor is a hyperlink denoted with the a tag. The anatomy of a hyperlink includes the destination address (defined by the href attribute), any additional attributes, and the anchor text. Anchor text is the linked text content that’s visible on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;“https://brandoncaples.com/blog/seo/”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;What is SEO?&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anchor text is important for SEO, specifically for the destination address. The anchor text should ideally include a keyword important to the destination address. For example, a page linking to this blog post might call that link “SEO terms explained” or “SEO glossary” in order to help my post rank better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason it works this way is simple: social affirmation. If another website vouches for my page’s credibility as a good resource for “SEO terms explained”, then Google and other search engines can feel confident that it’s a helpful page to show for that search term. And the more “social affirmation” a page receives—multiple related websites linking to my page with similar anchor text—the greater the chance for an excellent page rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backlinks&quot;&gt;Backlinks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backlinks are web links coming to your site from other websites. Search engines used to rank websites according to their numbers of backlinks, but that algorithm was quickly exploited by people with dozens—even hundreds—of micro-sites that served no purpose except to link to a main site. The number of backlinks to your website is probably still a major factor, but the key is having quality backlinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the word related in the last section? That’s important for quality backlinks. While you should strive to produce the kind of website that others want to link to, having a few dozen links from reputable, secure websites in your industry is much more preferable than having a lot of links from random, unsecured sites with no relation to what your website is about. For example, if you’re a food blogger trying to rank your website, you should want backlinks from restaurant websites, food truck associations, and other food blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engines keep their algorithms under lock and key, so it’s hard to say just how important quality backlinks are, but there’s substantial evidence to suggest that backlinks are a primary pillar of search engine optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;canonical-reference&quot;&gt;Canonical Reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canonical reference is a tag that references a duplicate web page that should be considered more important than the current page. For example, say I want to reconfigure my URL structure to make blog post URLs shorter. (It’s widely believed that search engines prefer shorter URLs.) Since my blog posts have been indexed by Google for years, those URLs might have some pretty nice page ranks. I have a few options in this scenario:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep the old and new blog posts online, but add a noindex value to the old posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the old blog posts and redirect those URLs to the new blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep the old and new posts, and set canonical tags to the new URLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding noindex to the old blog posts is a waste of page authority. Redirecting those old URLs will pass page rank onto the new URLs, but if redirection isn’t a viable option, using a canonical reference is a great solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicate content causes Google and other search engines to have to decide which of the duplicates is most helpful to searchers and should therefore be ranked. The likely winner is the older page; the other will get flagged as duplicate content, which will hurt the rank of the entire domain. But by placing canonical tags on the old pages, I can tell search engines that the new pages should get the ranking credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;click-through-rate-ctr&quot;&gt;Click-Through Rate (CTR)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A click-through rate (CTR) is the percentage of instances in which a searcher is shown a particular search result and clicks it. The click-through rate is a ranking factor for Google, because clicking a result after typing a keyword into the search bar tells the search engine, “Hey, this is what I was looking for.” The search engine then associates that web page a little more closely with the keyword used to find it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meta-description&quot;&gt;Meta Description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meta description is the short paragraph that appears below the title of a search result. It describes the content of the page to the person searching. Google announced in 2009 that meta descriptions do not directly affect search engine rankings, but they can impact click-through rates. Think of the meta description as the elevator pitch for your web page. This elevator pitch should entice the person to click onto the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google increased the length of meta descriptions on its search engine results pages last year from about 160 characters to about 320 characters. Marketers were ecstatic. But only a few short months later, Google had changed its mind and reverted back, leaving people scrambling to shorten the descriptions they had just lengthened. I now recommend about 155 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;robots&quot;&gt;Robots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google and other search engines inspect your web pages using robots—a.k.a. bots, spiders, or crawlers—that “crawl” pages and report on what they find. This helps search engines know what a page is about in order to show it to searchers on the search engine results page (SERP). These robots read all kinds of content and check for specific elements of a page to get information. If a particular piece of information is missing, it can affect how a page ranks on the SERP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engine bots don’t have nearly the cognitive processing power of the human brain, so it’s crucial for search engine optimization that your web pages contain information that’s readable by robots. That’s why the SEO terms explained in this glossary are important. If a search engine can’t tell clearly what a page is about, it won’t rank that page well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-robotstxt&quot;&gt;Using robots.txt&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important way to communicate with search engine bots is with a document called robots.txt, which should be placed in the root directory of your website. If you’re using WordPress or another content management system (CMS), there are plugins and add-ons that can help you with this. However, you can avoid downloading a plugin if you have access to your website files and want to create this document manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;noindex&quot;&gt;noindex&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indexing is what happens when a search engine like Google lists a web page in its search engine results pages (SERP). But what if you don’t want a particular page to appear in search results? A prime example is a thank-you page that a user might see after completing a web form. It would be weird if someone accidentally stumbled onto your thank-you page when they haven’t interacted with your website before. Even worse, what if that page contains a download in exchange for contact information?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to add a noindex value to a robots meta tag. It looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;meta&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;robots&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;content=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;noindex&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tells search engines not to index the page. It’s that simple. (You could also replace the value robots with a specific bot name, like googlebot, to allow every search engine except Google to index the page.) But you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-dont-mix-noindex-relcanonical/262607/&quot;&gt;never use both noindex and a canonical reference on the same page&lt;/a&gt;. According to Google’s John Mueller, this will force Google to choose which signal to honor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that noindex, and other search engine signals, are only requests. Google, Bing, and other reputable search engines will honor these requests, but other, less honorable bots can still crawl your site and see your pages. If you want to truly hide a page, it should be password-protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;nofollow&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you might need to link to another website without associating it with your own site. You can use nofollow for that. Using nofollow on a link tells search engines not to follow the link and pass link authority to the other web page. This is useful if the link leads to a nonsecure website, a site that’s not related to your industry, or if it’s a paid link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sitemap&quot;&gt;Sitemap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google and other search engines “crawl” the web by following links from one page to another and from one domain to another. If you have a new website with few, if any, links pointing to it, a sitemap will come in handy. A sitemap is an XML document written for robots that lists all the URLs of a website. Search engines will crawl your website if they can regardless of the the presence of a sitemap, but it helps them index a site’s pages quicker and keeps things organized. A sitemap acts kind of like a directory in the lobby of a large office building, pointing robots to where they should go and avoiding a page being missed if, for instance, there’s no link pointing to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document can be created in WordPress easily with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/wordpress-seo/&quot;&gt;Yoast SEO plugin&lt;/a&gt;. If your site isn’t built with WordPress, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&quot;&gt;XML-Sitemaps.com&lt;/a&gt; to create a sitemap. Next, you need to let search engines know about your sitemap by referencing it in your robots.txt file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Sitemap: https://www.example.com/sitemap.xml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can submit your sitemap to Google and other search engines directly. One thing to make sure of is that the information you’re giving to search engines is consistent. Don’t block a page in robots.txt and then list it in your sitemap. A sitemap should contain all the pages that should be indexed by a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;title-tag&quot;&gt;Title tag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meta title is very important. It’s, well, the title of your web page. Like a book title, it sums up the whole web page. It tells everyone—humans and robots alike—what the page is about. Search engines use this basic piece of information to determine whether your web page is worth showing to a searcher seeking answers online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your meta title should be fairly short. Google tends to display titles between 50 and 60 characters. I recommend a meta title length of no more than 55 characters. You don’t want search engines to cut your title short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meta title should also contain the keyword you’re targeting for the page, preferably at the beginning of the title. The title will display on search engine results pages and in the browser tab when someone visits the page. This is how the HTML should be displayed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Here’s an Awesome Title | Brandon Caples&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many websites also place the title in the content of the page for viewers to see. If you want it on the viewable part of the web page, put it in an H1 tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Here’s an Awesome Title&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization can be as simple as writing good content and linking to helpful resources, or as complicated as multiple lines of schema markup on every page of a website. Regardless of your particular approach to SEO, it’s helpful to know what these terms can mean for your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more SEO resources, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo&quot;&gt;Moz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://neilpatel.com/what-is-seo/&quot;&gt;Neil Patel&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.searchenginejournal.com/seo-guide/&quot;&gt;Search Engine Journal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="SEO" /><summary type="html">Search engine optimization (SEO) can be very complicated, and even small changes to search engines’ algorithms can cause panic in the marketing community. There’s an entire SEO industry of professionals who spend 100% of their time optimizing websites for clients. But not everyone can afford to hire an SEO agency, so it’s helpful to have SEO terms explained in plain English for those of us who plan to get our hands dirty.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to draw a heart in Inkscape</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2019/inkscape-heart" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to draw a heart in Inkscape" /><published>2019-02-14T09:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2019/inkscape-heart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2019/inkscape-heart">&lt;p&gt;Inkscape is a free vector graphics editor, similar to Adobe Illustrator, just without a few bells and whistles. The free, open source editor can accomplish a lot, though. Today, we’re going to learn how to draw a heart using Inkscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a small business often means finding free alternatives to otherwise pricey tasks. Inkscape is a great alternative to Illustrator, and many tasks can be completed quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;a aria-label=&quot;download Inkscape (opens in a new tab)&quot; href=&quot;https://inkscape.org/release/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener&quot;&gt;download Inkscape&lt;/a&gt; and open a new document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-1.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-1.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A new Inkscape document&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the Circle tool to draw an ellipse, or circle. Hold down the Control button as you click and drag the cursor to draw a perfect circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-2.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-2.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink circle drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, draw a rectangle that is the same height as the circle and half its width. Align the two shapes along their right edges and centered vertically. (You can align objects by selecting “Align and Distribute…” from the &lt;strong&gt;Object&lt;/strong&gt; menu.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-3.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-3.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A blue rectangle placed on top of a pink circle, drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both objects are currently classified as shapes, but we need to convert them both to paths for the next steps. With both objects selected, choose “Object to Path” from the &lt;strong&gt;Path&lt;/strong&gt; menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-4.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-4.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Inkscape context menu with Object to Path selected&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With both objects still selected and the rectangle sitting above the circle, select &lt;strong&gt;Path &amp;gt; Difference&lt;/strong&gt; to cut the circle in half using the rectangle as the difference. The rectangle will disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-5.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-5.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Inkscape context menu with Difference selected&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you do need to rearrange the order of your objects, use the Raise and Lower tools in the &lt;strong&gt;Object&lt;/strong&gt; menu.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we have so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-6.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-6.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink half-circle drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicate the half-circle (&lt;strong&gt;Edit &amp;gt; Duplicate&lt;/strong&gt;) and flip it horizontally (&lt;strong&gt;Object &amp;gt; Flip Horizontal&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-7.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-7.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink circle drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now draw a square with the same height and width as the circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-8.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-8.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink circle and a pink square, drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrange the half-circles and the square as shown below. It finally looks like a heart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-9.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-9.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink heart drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all three shapes in place and selected, select “Union” from the &lt;strong&gt;Path&lt;/strong&gt; menu. This merges all three shapes into one shape—a heart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-10.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-10.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Inkscape context menu with Union selected&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You now have a perfect heart shape that will scale infinitely and is easy to recolor. Simply rotate the heart 45° to stand it upright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-11.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/how-to-heart-11.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A pink heart drawn digitally with Inkscape software&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ve enjoyed learning how to draw a heart in Inkscape. Keep designing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="how to" /><category term="graphic design" /><summary type="html">Inkscape is a free vector graphics editor, similar to Adobe Illustrator, just without a few bells and whistles. The free, open source editor can accomplish a lot, though. Today, we’re going to learn how to draw a heart using Inkscape.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">God will restore what was lost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2018/god-will-restore-what-was-lost" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="God will restore what was lost" /><published>2018-10-30T05:45:47-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-30T05:45:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2018/god-will-restore-what-was-lost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2018/god-will-restore-what-was-lost">&lt;p class=&quot;note&quot;&gt;The original article, published on October 9, 2018, can be found at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mercymultiplied.com/god-will-restore-what-was-lost/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mercy Multiplied blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a heavy thing to consider what we’ve lost because of sin. When we turn from God and choose to live selfishly, there are often consequences, and in this life, some consequences are much worse than others, so it can be hard to imagine that God will restore what was lost during our times of disobedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;god-will-restore-what-was-lost&quot;&gt;God will restore what was lost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Deuteronomy 29, Moses delivers a stern rebuke of the people for turning away from God and worshiping false idols. They had been delivered out of Egypt and wandered in the wilderness for 40 years because of their disobedience, but their story didn’t end there. In the next chapter, Moses delivers hope for the people from God. If they will return to the Lord, &lt;q&gt;then the Lord your God will restore your fortunes and have mercy on you, and he will gather you again from all the peoples where the Lord your God has scattered you.&lt;/q&gt; (Deuteronomy 30:3, &lt;abbr title=&quot;English Standard Version&quot;&gt;ESV&lt;/abbr&gt;) When we turn toward God, He restores, even after a lifetime of separation from Him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;god-will-restore-the-lost-years&quot;&gt;God will restore the lost years&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first chapter of his book, the prophet Joel describes a plague of locusts that have devoured the land, consuming all the crops that the people and their animals depended on. They are in agony because they turned from the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Chapter 2, Joel calls on the people to mourn and repent. Joel 2:18 (ESV) says, &lt;q&gt;Then the LORD became jealous for his land and had pity on his people.&lt;/q&gt; God responded to their repentance with mercy, something we’re used to seeing throughout the Bible. He’s a very loving and merciful God. But then God told them something that can often get overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;I will restore to you the years that the swarming locust has eaten…&lt;/q&gt; (Joel 2:25, ESV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God promised to not only deliver the people from this plague and famine, but to give to them all that they would have had during that time—because they chose to come back to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-redeem-and-restore&quot;&gt;To redeem and restore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mercymultiplied.com/&quot;&gt;Mercy Multiplied&lt;/a&gt; walks alongside women ages 13–32 as they work to overcome life-controlling issues by the power of Christ. In my short time with this incredible group of people striving for a less broken world, I heard countless stories of redemption. God uses the pasts of these women as weapons against the enemy in unimaginable ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, God wants us all to bring our sin and shame to Him &lt;a href=&quot;https://mercymultiplied.com/2018/08/from-criminal-record-to-law-student/&quot;&gt;to redeem and restore&lt;/a&gt;. He will turn our past guilt into weapons for His glory, and like this passage from Joel, the time we’ve lost to shame and darkness will be restored to us. God will restore what was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduates of Mercy Multiplied have gone on to do amazing things that their families, Mercy staff, and they themselves couldn’t have imagined before Mercy Multiplied. They work in ministry, in business, they become speakers and authors, they go on to break the chains off of hurting people. All because they encountered the living God who restores what has been lost.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="restoration" /><summary type="html">The original article, published on October 9, 2018, can be found at the Mercy Multiplied blog.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is SEO?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2018/what-is-seo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is SEO?" /><published>2018-09-15T20:47:59-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-15T20:47:59-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2018/what-is-seo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2018/what-is-seo">&lt;p&gt;Most small business owners and marketers are constantly thinking of new ways to promote their business. One of the most affordable and effective tools is a well-crafted website and knowledge of search engine optimization (SEO). But what is SEO exactly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engine optimization (SEO) involves making strategic and technical adjustments to your website structure and your web pages in order to earn higher rankings on search engine results pages (SERP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can take a lot of time and energy to get SEO done right, but Google and other search engines genuinely want their search engine results pages to be helpful. While they guard their algorithms closely, the search engines want truly relevant content to be found, regardless of the size of the organization or website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;search-engines&quot;&gt;Search engines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engines are complex algorithms that act as matchmakers between searchers and web pages. Although search engine algorithms are very advanced these days, the goal is clear: to help a searcher find exactly what they’re looking for. Search engines scour the internet to index content to serve up on search engine results pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These algorithms are kept under lock and key, but what we do know is that each search is very unique. Searching for the exact same keyword in Lincoln, CA and Nashville, TN will produce different results. The searcher’s browsing and search history can also be factors. On top of that, web pages and their domains are constantly changing in the eyes of a search engine. Rankings fluctuate based on many different factors that Google and other search engines consider important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-search&quot;&gt;Google search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may notice that I refer to Google a lot more than other search engines. The reason is that Google pretty much owns the search market. &lt;a href=&quot;http://gs.statcounter.com/search-engine-market-share&quot;&gt;According to StatCounter&lt;/a&gt;, Google’s share of the search engine market is nearly 91%. As a society, we even turned &lt;em&gt;google&lt;/em&gt; into a verb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Search, or Google Web Search, is the most popular search engine, by far, with more than three billion searches each day. The search engine is 21 years old today (launched September 15, 1997) and performs searches in 197 languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;robots&quot;&gt;Robots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might ask, “So how does Google know how relevant my web page is?” The answer: robots. Not the science fiction kind, but the computer code kind. Each search engine has its own robot; some of them have multiple bots. And while they certainly are taking over the digital world, they seem to be friendly, so not to worry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These robots crawl a website’s pages collecting data to determine what the website and its pages are about. These bots are pretty smart, but they still have nowhere near the cognitive processing power of the human brain. That’s why it’s so important to structure your pages in ways that robots can read and understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keywords&quot;&gt;Keywords&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A keyword is a search term used in a search engine like Google. Though the term keyword originally referred to a single word, it now represents anything a person types into the search bar. So it could be something like “shoes” or “best running shoes in nashville tn”. Both are considered keywords. The second, longer term is called a long-tail keyword. This is the type of keyword you should be targeting as a small business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long-tail keyword is a more specific search term that targets a niche and is therefore less competitive on the search engine results page. It’s generally considered to be at least three words long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why target long-tail keywords? There’s less competition. There are fewer web pages out there targeting a particular long-tail keyword, so when a searcher types it into the search bar, your page is more likely to show up. Furthermore, somewhere in the neighborhood of 70% of searches are for long-tail terms, because people know what they’re looking for, and they are specific in their searches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-a-good-citizen-of-the-web&quot;&gt;Be a good citizen of the web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEO is a complex subject, but it can also be simple. I like to tell people that if they’re a good “citizen of the web” they can rank well, but there are some technical aspects of a web page, too, that help search engines determine how relevant the page is for someone searching for something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEO is a legitimate practice, so don’t think that the goal is to manipulate search engines into ranking your site closer to the search bar. The major search engines have gotten really good at determining if a page is using bad practices like keyword stuffing or hiding content. Misleading titles and descriptions won’t help you, either. If a searcher clicks on your result from Google and realizes the page or site isn’t what they thought it was, they will leave. Not only is this person frustrated that you didn’t give them what they wanted, but Google now knows that this page isn’t a good result, so the page will rank lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-seo&quot;&gt;So what is SEO?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an ongoing process. SEO is a journey with no destination. It can be both fun and frustrating, but if you’re truly committed to providing meaningful content on your website, applying a little bit of SEO magic can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="SEO" /><category term="Google" /><summary type="html">Most small business owners and marketers are constantly thinking of new ways to promote their business. One of the most affordable and effective tools is a well-crafted website and knowledge of search engine optimization (SEO). But what is SEO exactly?</summary></entry></feed>