<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-07T22:09:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">capncapes.github.io</title><subtitle>A blog site built with Jekyll consisting of two blogs, a feed of book reviews, and other content pages.</subtitle><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><entry><title type="html">Image and dominion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/image-and-dominion" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Image and dominion" /><published>2023-03-05T16:59:16-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-05T16:59:16-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/image-and-dominion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/image-and-dominion">&lt;p&gt;What informs your identity? Like most people, it’s a few things for me. I’m a husband and father, a Christ follower, a son, a brother, a digital marketer and website developer, a hobbyist woodworker, and a resident of Tennessee, among other characteristics that contribute to my identity. But which takes precedent? Certainly some parts of my identity are less important than others. What’s at the core of my identity? We can look to the Bible for answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So God created mankind in his own image, in the image of God he created them; male and female he created them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 1:27, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hebrew word in 1:27 translated as &lt;em&gt;mankind&lt;/em&gt; refers to both men and women. We are &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; created in his image—this is our foundational identity, that we are made in the image of God! But what does that even mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ancient world, bearing the image of God would connote the idea of a vice-regency. This is a person who represents and speaks on behalf of a king or ruler. So to be created in the image of God means that our primary identity is in glorifying God in everything we do. King David explains this concept in Psalm 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;davids-interpretation-of-the-creation-mandate-in-psalm-8&quot;&gt;David’s interpretation of the creation mandate in Psalm 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For the director of music. According to &lt;em&gt;gittith&lt;/em&gt;. A psalm of David.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Lord, our Lord,&lt;br /&gt;
how majestic is your name in all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;You have set your glory&lt;br /&gt;
in the heavens.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Through the praise of children and infants&lt;br /&gt;
you have established a stronghold against your enemies,&lt;br /&gt;
to silence the foe and the avenger.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; When I consider your heavens,&lt;br /&gt;
the work of your fingers,&lt;br /&gt;
the moon and the stars,&lt;br /&gt;
which you have set in place,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; what is mankind that you are mindful of them,&lt;br /&gt;
human beings that you care for them?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; You have made them a little lower than the angels&lt;br /&gt;
and crowned them with glory and honor.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; You made them rulers over the works of your hands;&lt;br /&gt;
you put everything under their feet:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; all flocks and herds,&lt;br /&gt;
and the animals of the wild,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; the birds in the sky,&lt;br /&gt;
and the fish in the sea,&lt;br /&gt;
all that swim the paths of the seas.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; Lord, our Lord,&lt;br /&gt;
how majestic is your name in all the earth!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 8, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James M. Hamilton Jr., a professor of biblical theology at The Southern Baptist Theological Seminary, reads Psalm 8 as both a personal mandate for image bearers and a Christological shadow. In Volume I of his commentary on the Psalms&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Hamilton translates verse 4 differently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; What is man [&lt;em&gt;Enosh&lt;/em&gt;] that you remember him, the son of Adam that you visit him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Hebrew, both Adam and Enosh mean &lt;em&gt;man&lt;/em&gt;. Noting the psalmist’s geneological reference to the first three generations of humanity (Adam &amp;gt; Seth &amp;gt; Enosh), Hamilton traces David’s intent back to the garden of Eden and the curse of the serpent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;And I will put enmity between you and the woman, and between your offspring and hers; he will crush your head, and you will strike his heel.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Genesis 3:16, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Psalm 8 is quite short, it reveals a lot about David’s understanding of God’s promise in Genesis 3: &lt;strong&gt;the seed of the woman will crush the head of evil.&lt;/strong&gt; And recognizing that he himself sits in that lineage, he can’t keep his praises from bursting forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psalm 8 is a poem of adoration for Yahweh’s faithfulness. David wrote this psalm with a keen awareness of his own lineage from Adam, as well as his God-given dominion. Hamilton writes, &lt;q&gt;David understands the purpose of his dominion to be the extension of Yahweh’s glory, and he understands that dominion to be in conflict with the way &lt;q&gt;the enemy and the avenger&lt;/q&gt; seeks to establish his own dominion through the kings of the nations who set themselves against Yahweh and his anointed (2:1–3).&lt;/q&gt; The words of Psalm 8:6–9 are an obvious reference to Genesis 1:28, when God gives Adam and Eve dominion over all creation for the purpose of glorifying God. &lt;strong&gt;This is David’s interpretation of image bearing and dominion in the first chapters of Genesis.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mans-identity-in-the-book-of-job&quot;&gt;Man’s identity in the book of Job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book of Job is a phenomenal thesis on identity. Set in the midst of the worst days of Job’s life, his own friends blame him for his suffering, which was allowed by God to prove Job’s faithfulness. Toward the end of the book (chapters 38–39), God addresses Job directly from a whirlwind, mostly with rhetorical questions responding to Job’s questions of God’s justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Where were you when I laid the earth’s foundation?&lt;br /&gt;
Tell me, if you understand.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Who marked off its dimensions? Surely you know!&lt;br /&gt;
Who stretched a measuring line across it?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; On what were its footings set,&lt;br /&gt;
or who laid its cornerstone—&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; while the morning stars sang together&lt;br /&gt;
and all the angels shouted for joy?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Job 38:4–7, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John H. Walton, a leading Old Testament scholar, points out that this section of the book of Job—and the creation account in Genesis—is not scientific in nature. That’s not why it was written or how its original readers would have interpreted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In [Job 38–41], Yahweh is not seeking to prove his existence. He is making the point that it is foolhardy to call him to task for his putative failure to conform to a system of human devising that has access to so little data.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John H. Walton, The NIV Application Commentary: Job&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does God’s poetic language in Job 38–39 put Job “in his place”—it also serves to remind Job, and us, that God &lt;q&gt;provides food for the raven&lt;/q&gt; (38:41, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;) and knows &lt;q&gt;when the mountain goats give birth.&lt;/q&gt; (39:1, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;) Surely the God who watches and cares for his creatures so well cares deeply for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;living-in-light-of-image-and-dominion&quot;&gt;Living in light of image and dominion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken together, Genesis 1–3, Job 38–39, and Psalm 8 remind us that, as image bearers of the Almighty, we have the capacity to do for others what God does for his whole creation—bring Light into their lives, restore order from chaos, water the deserts of their souls, cherish &lt;q&gt;the least of these,&lt;/q&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and care for all within our purview. Simply put, we represent our Father in heaven as his imagers on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God breathed his breath of life into us, not just to make us alive—the animals became alive without this breath of life—but to stir us to live, to do, to act, as his representatives on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has given each of us dominion over something, and that authority is best practiced when we look to our God and King, our Good Shepherd. Authority is not for dominating those around us—it’s for caring well for them. God provides for the birds, the wildflowers, and the sheep of his fold. What God does for the cosmos, he equips us to do for our communities. &lt;strong&gt;This is our identity: we are made in the image of our good God for the purpose of caring for creation, most especially our fellow people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what now? &lt;q&gt;Go and do the same.&lt;/q&gt; (The words of Jesus found in Luke 10:37, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Christian Standard Bible&quot;&gt;CSB&lt;/abbr&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hamilton, J. M., Jr. (2021). &lt;em&gt;Psalms Volume I: Evangelical Biblical Theology Commentary.&lt;/em&gt; Faithlife Corporation. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See Matthew 25:31–46. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="image of God" /><summary type="html">What informs your identity? Like most people, it’s a few things for me. I’m a husband and father, a Christ follower, a son, a brother, a digital marketer and website developer, a hobbyist woodworker, and a resident of Tennessee, among other characteristics that contribute to my identity. But which takes precedent? Certainly some parts of my identity are less important than others. What’s at the core of my identity? We can look to the Bible for answers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The structure and chronology of the book of Daniel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/structure-book-daniel" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The structure and chronology of the book of Daniel" /><published>2023-02-07T21:30:01-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-07T21:30:01-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/structure-book-daniel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2023/structure-book-daniel">&lt;p&gt;The book of Daniel is a testament to God’s sovereign rule over all kingdoms and peoples. In twelve chapters, the book describes the aftermath of Nebuchadnezzar’s conquest of Jerusalem, focusing on events and visions in the reigns of several rulers during the life of Daniel, the main figure of this apocalyptic book. Shortly after arriving in exile in Babylon, Daniel was given the name Belteshazzar, which honors one of the Babylonian gods. Daniel spent his entire life in Babylonia, though he knew through dreams and visions from Yahweh that his people would not be doomed to exile forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book of Daniel describes many events and mysteries, and Daniel is empowered by God to interpret signs, wonders, dreams, and visions for the various rulers of Babylonia. The book can easily be divided into two halves. Chapters 1–6 are historical, and chapters 7–12 describe prophecies. But the chapters don’t flow chronologically, which is easy to miss without paying close attention to time references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the book of Daniel flows chronologically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
	&lt;thead&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Ch.&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;King/Kingdom&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Theme&lt;/th&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/thead&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;1&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;607 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Jehoiakim/Judah&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Nebuchadnezzar&apos;s conquest of Judah&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;2&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;604 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Nebuchadnezzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s knowledge and interpretation of Nebuchadnezzar&apos;s first dream&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;3&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;604 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Nebuchadnezzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;The fiery furnace&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;4&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;604 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Nebuchadnezzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Nebuchadnezzar&apos;s madness&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;7&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;553 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Belshazzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s first vision (four beasts and &lt;q&gt;a son of man&lt;/q&gt; riding the clouds)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;8&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;550 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Belshazzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s second vision (ram and goat, representing Medo-Persia and Greece)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;5&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;539 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Belshazzar/Babylonia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;The divine handwriting on the wall&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;6&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;539 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Darius/Medo-Persia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel in the lion&apos;s den&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;9&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;539 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Darius/Medo-Persia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s prayer and third vision (70 weeks)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;10&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;536 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Cyrus/Persia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s fourth vision (future days)&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;11&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;536 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Cyrus/Persia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s fourth vision (future days), continued&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr class=&quot;text-xs&quot;&gt;
			&lt;th scope=&quot;row&quot; class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;12&lt;/th&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;536 BC&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Cyrus/Persia&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Daniel&apos;s fourth vision (future days), continued&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first six chapters of Daniel are easily the most identifiable. Even non-Christians can recognize the stories of the lion’s den, the fiery furnace, and the handwriting on the wall. But the second half of the book includes powerful prophecies delivered to Daniel in dreams and visions. His first vision, in chapter 7, provides a favorite name of Jesus for himself: Son of Man.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Through three more visions, Daniel learns of the future for Babylonia, the Israelite exiles, and the nation of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an apocalyptic book, Daniel includes references to angels—Michael and Gabriel—the heavenly court of Yahweh, and future events. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.precept.org/collections/daniel-in-out-nasb/products/daniel-part-1-in-out-workbook-nasb-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Studying the book of Daniel&lt;/a&gt; is fascinating for this reason alone, as it pulls back the curtain and reveals much of how the physical and spiritual realms relate to one another. It’s beneficial to study Revelation while studying Daniel, as the two depict some of the same events. And with a reading time of about an hour and fifteen minutes, Daniel is an excellent choice for a medium-length Bible study that will certainly offer comfort and hope to any who feel alientated within their culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Read chapter 7 for yourself; it’s incredible. I also recommend a book by Michael Heiser called &lt;em&gt;The Unseen Realm&lt;/em&gt;, which devotes a chapter to the significance of Daniel 7 in the Israelite-Babylonian context. Read my &lt;a href=&quot;/book-reviews/unseen-realm#the-rider-of-the-clouds&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;book review on &lt;em&gt;The Unseen Realm&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to get the gist of Heiser’s work. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="Daniel" /><category term="prophecy" /><summary type="html">The book of Daniel is a testament to God’s sovereign rule over all kingdoms and peoples. In twelve chapters, the book describes the aftermath of Nebuchadnezzar’s conquest of Jerusalem, focusing on events and visions in the reigns of several rulers during the life of Daniel, the main figure of this apocalyptic book. Shortly after arriving in exile in Babylon, Daniel was given the name Belteshazzar, which honors one of the Babylonian gods. Daniel spent his entire life in Babylonia, though he knew through dreams and visions from Yahweh that his people would not be doomed to exile forever.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using dates with SQL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-dates" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using dates with SQL" /><published>2023-01-18T12:00:01-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-18T12:00:01-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-dates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-dates">&lt;p&gt;Working with dates in SQL is a pretty common task, and there are several date functions that we can use to query results and manipulate data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now&quot;&gt;NOW()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NOW()&lt;/code&gt; function simply returns the current datetime, like this: &lt;strong&gt;2023-03-07 22:09:33&lt;/strong&gt;. You will probably use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NOW()&lt;/code&gt; a lot. If you only need the current date or the current time, use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CURDATE()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CURTIME()&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getdate&quot;&gt;GETDATE()&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GETDATE()&lt;/code&gt; function works exactly like the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NOW()&lt;/code&gt; function, except that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GETDATE()&lt;/code&gt; returns milliseconds, too. The query result would look something like this: &lt;strong&gt;2023-03-07 22:09:33.847&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;date&quot;&gt;DATE()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATE(date)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATE()&lt;/code&gt; function to extract the date from a valid date expression. The return format is &lt;strong&gt;YYYY-MM-DD&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a useful function when handling mismatched date formats, especially if you don’t need to work with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dateadd&quot;&gt;DATEADD()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEADD(interval, number, date)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEADD()&lt;/code&gt; function is used to add (or subtract) two dates. The interval can be any of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;year (also yyyy or yy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quarter (also qq or q)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;month (also mm or m)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dayofyear (also dy or y)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;day (also dd or d)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;week (also ww or wk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;weekday (also dw or w)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hour (also hh)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minute (also mi or n)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;second (also ss or s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;millisecond (also ms)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;microsecond (also mcs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nanosecond (also ns)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number parameter should be the number of the interval parameter needed, and it can be either positive (future) or negative (past).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following example returns a date value that’s eight days in the past, from the current moment in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DATEADD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;day&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GETDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;datepart&quot;&gt;DATEPART()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEPART(interval, date)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEPART()&lt;/code&gt; returns a specified part of a date. Use the interval parameter to specify the return value. The interval can be any of the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;year (also yyyy or yy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quarter (also qq or q)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;month (also mm or m)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dayofyear (also dy or y)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;day (also dd or d)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;week (also ww or wk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;weekday (also dw or w)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hour (also hh)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minute (also mi or n)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;second (also ss or s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;millisecond (also ms)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;microsecond (also mcs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;nanosecond (also ns)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tzoffset (timezone offset, also tz)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iso_week (ISO week, also isowk or isoww)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;datediff&quot;&gt;DATEDIFF()&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEDIFF(interval, date1, date2)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DATEDIFF&lt;/code&gt; function to return the difference between two dates. The return value can be any of the following specified intervals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;year (also yyyy or yy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quarter (also qq or q)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;month (also mm or m)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dayofyear&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;day (also dy or y)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;week (also ww or wk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;weekday (also dw or w)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hour (also hh)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minute (also mi or n)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;second (also ss or s)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;millisecond (also ms)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function starts with the first date provided, and the result can be either positive or negative depending on which direction in time the calculation moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;-- Find all people older than 40.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DATEDIFF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;NOW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;365&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important thing to remember when working with dates in SQL is that date formats need to match between the database column and the intended result. For a primer on working with SQL, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;/martech/2023/sql-intro&quot;&gt;introduction to SQL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="SQL" /><category term="data science" /><summary type="html">Working with dates in SQL is a pretty common task, and there are several date functions that we can use to query results and manipulate data.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to SQL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-intro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to SQL" /><published>2023-01-04T07:25:30-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T07:25:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2023/sql-intro">&lt;p&gt;Structured Query Language (SQL) was developed by IBM researchers in the 1970s. SQL—sometimes pronounced “sequel”—is used to store, retrieve, and manipulate data in databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many data management systems have user-friendly ways to export entire sets of data, or sometimes just the transactions from a date range, for example, but what if you need a list of records with very specific criteria?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you need a list of every person in your database who has been an email subscriber for the past six months, hasn’t purchased anything, lives in California, and has a birthday next month. You could use a spreadsheet to filter the list down, but that’s very time-consuming, especially if you need this list regularly. That’s where SQL can help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could build a SQL query for this and re-use it every time that specific list is needed. Depending on your marketing software, you could even automate this task, scheduling the SQL to run hourly, daily, or weekly to update your list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL is also used to display data on a webpage. WordPress uses MySQL to query data and display it on the website, and a custom query written by a developer can display very specific data for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started-with-sql-queries&quot;&gt;Getting started with SQL queries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A SQL query should start with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/code&gt; keyword, followed by the columns to be queried, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/code&gt; keyword, and the name of the table to query.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;FirstName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastName&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;contacts&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;EmailOptIn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;EmailOptOut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice in the example that the columns (Id, Email, FirstName, LastName) are separated by commas. You do not need to separate columns (or even new clauses) with line breaks, however, but it’s a good idea as a way to keep your SQL human-readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/code&gt; keyword designates the table, contacts, from which the columns are queried. Everything after &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FROM contacts&lt;/code&gt; in the above example is part of a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; clause, which we will explore later in this article. This query simply searches the table called contacts for the data in the specified columns and filters the query to only select contacts who are opted into email communication, are not opted out, and who have a value in the Email column (not null).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: In SQL, there is a difference between null and an empty string (‘’). It’s usually a good idea to check for both when validating data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aliases&quot;&gt;Aliases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SQL, an alias is a column name that is defined within the query. By default, columns in the results table are titled based on the field name. But you can change the title of a column by using an alias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the field name is &lt;strong&gt;email_address_contact&lt;/strong&gt;, you can rename it in the results to &lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt; by placing the alias immediately after the actual column name. You can optionally use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/code&gt; keyword for readability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following examples will both change the column title to &lt;strong&gt;Email&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;email_address_contact&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;email_address_contact&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;people&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliases become really helpful when using functions. A SQL function can cause problems if it shows up in the results table when working with a programming language like PHP to display results on a webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last note on aliases: It’s possible to create column aliases with spaces by enclosing the alias in single quotes. This can improve readability, but again, some programming languages may have difficulty handling column titles with spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;filtering-a-query&quot;&gt;Filtering a query&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to filter a query for specific criteria, use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/code&gt; clause, followed by one or more conditions. A condition should have a field, a comparison operator of some kind, and a value or range of values to check for. If using multiple conditions, separate them with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;OR&lt;/code&gt; keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;FirstName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;First&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;Last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Birthdate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CustomerSince&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Customer Anniversary&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;people&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Birthdate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;1980-12-31&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;LEFT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;FirstName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;B&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;Last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;LIKE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;_a%&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Caples&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CustomerSince&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;2020-01-01&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Birthdate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the use of parentheses to distinguish between condition groups. The example is searching the database for records matching any of the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Birthdate is after 1980 and the first initial of FirstName is B&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LastName contains any one letter(“_”), with the second letter being A, followed by one or more unspecified characters (“%”)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LastName equals Caples and CustomerSince is a date equal to or after January 1, 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a record meets any of those conditions, it will be returned in the results table if it also meets the condition that the Birthdate field is not null. (To find records that are null, use IS NULL in the condition.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-types&quot;&gt;Data types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three primary data types in SQL: string, numeric, and date/time. Each of these data types has multiple subtypes within it. A good resource for information about each data type can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/mysql/mysql_datatypes.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;W3Schools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at our earlier example querying people who meet the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Email subscriber for past 6 months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zero purchases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lives in California&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has a birthday next month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sql&quot; data-lang=&quot;sql&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;FirstName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastName&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;contacts&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DateSubscribed&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DATEADD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GETDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastPurchaseDate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;‘’&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;OR&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;LastPurchaseDate&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;AddressState&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;‘&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;’&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DATEPART&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Dob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;DATEADD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;month&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;GETDATE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;EmailOptIn&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;EmailOptOut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;IS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NOT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this query, we can capture this list of people and send an email inviting them to a product event near them with a free birthday gift offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that we don’t actually need to count the number of purchases on the customer’s record—only whether there’s a value for &lt;strong&gt;LastPurchaseDate&lt;/strong&gt;. You can get creative with your SQL queries to prevent unnecessary clauses. And be sure to look up all of the functions and keywords used in these examples, since I haven’t explained them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to remember that a SQL query depends on the data available in the database. If we don’t have a column for the date a person subscribes to emails, or if a contact has missing birthdate data, for example, our query will be limited and less reliable. Clean data systems are very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more functions and features within SQL, but this is just an introduction. There are a lot of good websites for learning SQL, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/learn/learn-sql&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://learnsql.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LearnSQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackskills.com/p/sql-for-marketers&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;StackSkills&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3schools.com/sql/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;W3Schools&lt;/a&gt;. (Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sqltutorial.org/sql-cheat-sheet/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;free SQL cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;!) You can also find good tutorials on YouTube and solutions on StackOverflow. There are plenty of resources to help you learn the basics (and more) of Structured Query Language.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="SQL" /><category term="data science" /><summary type="html">Structured Query Language (SQL) was developed by IBM researchers in the 1970s. SQL—sometimes pronounced “sequel”—is used to store, retrieve, and manipulate data in databases.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is systematic theology?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/systematic-theology-scripture" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is systematic theology?" /><published>2022-12-16T16:12:59-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-16T16:12:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/systematic-theology-scripture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/systematic-theology-scripture">&lt;p&gt;This article represents my collection of notes and personal thoughts on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rts.edu/resources/scripture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Basics of Systematic Theology: Scripture” lecture&lt;/a&gt; by Scott R. Swain, Ph.D. at Reformed Theological Seminary in 2017. All unattributed quotations are those of Dr. Swain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/faith/scott-swain.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/faith/scott-swain.jpg&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Scott Swain lecturing on systematic theology&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-systematic-theology&quot;&gt;What is systematic theology?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, systematic theology may seem very dry, as if the stories and messages found within the Bible are pulled out and systematized into stale Latin phrases by dead theologians. But systematic theology is much richer. It’s a way of studying a subject in context throughout the entirety of Scripture, attending to the cohesiveness of texts separated by thousands of years, dozens of authors, and multiple languages and cultures. In his lecture introducing systematic theology, Scott R. Swain highlights four key principles: unity, scope, proportion, and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unity&quot;&gt;Unity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do the books of the Bible relate to one another to form a unified message? &lt;q&gt;In systematic theology, we ask not just, ‘What does Paul say in Romans,’ but, ‘how does what Paul says in Romans relate to what Moses says in Exodus?’&lt;/q&gt; Furthermore, the principle of unity in systematic theology also attempts to relate the teachings of the Bible with science and philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-scope&quot;&gt;Full scope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systematic theology attempts to read and interpret Scripture in light of the rest of Scripture. In Acts 20, while addressing the elders of the church in Ephesus, Paul declares that he &lt;q&gt;did not shrink from declaring to you the whole counsel of God.&lt;/q&gt; (v. 27, ESV)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dutch Reformed theologian Herman Bavinck (1854–1921) noted that failure to observe the full scope of Scripture &lt;q&gt;leads to one-sidedness and error in theology and pathology in the religious life.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;proportions&quot;&gt;Proportions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott Swain illustrates the point that systematic theology observes biblical proportions in this way: &lt;q&gt;The Bible says something about everything… But the Bible doesn’t say everything about everything.&lt;/q&gt; There are first-order matters and second-order matters in Scripture.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As Paul points out in 1 Corinthians 15&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, the gospel is a matter of first importance. And though the Bible frequently mentions animals of various kinds, biblical information about animals is a matter of much lower importance than what the Bible says about human salvation. Systematic theology attempts to define those distinctions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relationships&quot;&gt;Relationships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth principle of systematic theology is concerned with the relationships between various doctrines. Swain uses the examples of good works and grace. Both of these doctrines are important to the Christian life. But how do good works and grace interact with each other? &lt;q&gt;If we think that good works are the basis for God’s grace, we’re going to get ourselves in all kinds of trouble.&lt;/q&gt; That’s because good works come after grace, not before. Systematic theology studies the relationships between doctrines in order to clarify each doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; For it is by grace you have been saved, through faith—and this is not from yourselves, it is the gift of God— &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; not by works, so that no one can boast. &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; For we are God’s handiwork, created in Christ Jesus to do good works, which God prepared in advance for us to do.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 2:8–10, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scripture&quot;&gt;Scripture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can the study of systematic theology tell us about Scripture? Is the Bible reliable and authoritative? Is it inspired by God or just a collection of writings by mortal men? Since all theological study necessarily deals primarily with holy texts, the study of Scripture itself is a good place to start. Swain employs three passages in order to observe how the Bible’s authors viewed Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;god-is-pleased-to-reveal-himself-to-us-in-order-that-we-might-find-rest-in-him&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;God is pleased to reveal himself to us in order that we might find rest in him.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt; At that time Jesus said, &lt;q&gt;I praise you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, because you have hidden these things from the wise and learned, and revealed them to little children. &lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt; Yes, Father, for this is what you were pleased to do. &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt; All things have been committed to me by my Father. No one knows the Son except the Father, and no one knows the Father except the Son and those to whom the Son chooses to reveal him. &lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt; Come to me, all you who are weary and burdened, and I will give you rest. &lt;sup&gt;29&lt;/sup&gt; Take my yoke upon you and learn from me, for I am gentle and humble in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. &lt;sup&gt;30&lt;/sup&gt; For my yoke is easy and my burden is light.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matthew 11:25–30, NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Matthew 11, we discover that the Godhead—Father, Son, Holy Spirit—are complete in their unity of knowledge and love with one another. This passage also teaches us that the Father delights in making himself known to his children. This knowledge of God that is revealed to us is not only for God’s good pleasure, but also so that we may find rest in him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;Augustine of Hippo&quot;&gt;You have made us for yourself, O Lord, and our hearts are restless until they rest in You.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
— Augustine, &lt;em&gt;Confessions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;god-is-pleased-to-reveal-himself-to-us-in-a-twofold-manner&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;God is pleased to reveal himself to us in a twofold manner.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; For the director of music. A psalm of David.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The heavens declare the glory of God;&lt;br /&gt;
the skies proclaim the work of his hands.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Day after day they pour forth speech;&lt;br /&gt;
night after night they reveal knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; They have no speech, they use no words;&lt;br /&gt;
no sound is heard from them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; Yet their voice goes out into all the earth,&lt;br /&gt;
their words to the ends of the world.&lt;br /&gt;
In the heavens God has pitched a tent for the sun.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; It is like a bridegroom coming out of his chamber,&lt;br /&gt;
like a champion rejoicing to run his course.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt; It rises at one end of the heavens&lt;br /&gt;
and makes its circuit to the other;&lt;br /&gt;
nothing is deprived of its warmth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; The law of the Lord is perfect,&lt;br /&gt;
refreshing the soul.&lt;br /&gt;
The statutes of the Lord are trustworthy,&lt;br /&gt;
making wise the simple.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; The precepts of the Lord are right,&lt;br /&gt;
giving joy to the heart.&lt;br /&gt;
The commands of the Lord are radiant,&lt;br /&gt;
giving light to the eyes.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; The fear of the Lord is pure,&lt;br /&gt;
enduring forever.&lt;br /&gt;
The decrees of the Lord are firm,&lt;br /&gt;
and all of them are righteous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; They are more precious than gold,&lt;br /&gt;
than much pure gold;&lt;br /&gt;
they are sweeter than honey,&lt;br /&gt;
than honey from the honeycomb.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt; By them your servant is warned;&lt;br /&gt;
in keeping them there is great reward.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt; But who can discern their own errors?&lt;br /&gt;
Forgive my hidden faults.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;sup&gt;13&lt;/sup&gt; Keep your servant also from willful sins;&lt;br /&gt;
may they not rule over me.&lt;br /&gt;
Then I will be blameless,&lt;br /&gt;
innocent of great transgression.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;14&lt;/sup&gt; May these words of my mouth and this meditation of my heart&lt;br /&gt;
be pleasing in your sight,&lt;br /&gt;
Lord, my Rock and my Redeemer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 19, NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Psalm 19, we can decipher two “books” by which we can know God: the book of nature and the book of Scripture. The Belgic Confession reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We know Him by two means: First, by the creation, preservation, and government of the universe; which is before our eyes as a most elegant book, wherein all creatures, great and small, are as so many characters leading us to see clearly the invisible things of God, even his everlasting power and divinity, as the apostle Paul says (Romans 1:20). All which things are sufficient to convince men and leave them without excuse. Second, He makes Himself more clearly and fully known to us by His holy and divine Word, that is to say, as far as is necessary for us to know in this life, to His glory and our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Belgic Confession, Article 2&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theological term “general revelation” is typically used of the work of the book of nature, while theologians use “special revelation” to describe knowledge that comes from the inspired Word of God, the book of Scripture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In verses 1–6 of Psalm 19, the natural world is said to &lt;q&gt;declare the glory of God&lt;/q&gt; (v. 1) and the psalmist makes use of metaphorical language to describe the eagerness of the sun to warm the whole earth. That’s general revelation, which describes human observance of the splendor of nature. General revelation is available to all audiences, but it is incomplete and cannot, by itself, bring us into a relationship with God. That’s where special revelation comes in. The psalmist references human anatomy in verses 7 and 8 to illustrate the incompleteness of the parts on their own &lt;em&gt;until&lt;/em&gt; they are brought together by the work of God’s law, statutes, and precepts. The soul, mind (v. 7), heart, and eyes (v. 8), themselves works of nature, are given refreshment, wisdom, joy, and light when introduced to the special revelation of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does Psalm 19 show us how these two books speak to us about God, but the psalmist also teaches us how we should speak back to God. In verses 12 and 13, he says, &lt;q&gt;But who can discern their own errors? Forgive my hidden faults. Keep your servant also from willful sins; may they not rule over me.&lt;/q&gt; The psalmist, King David, acknowledges that he is out of step with the rest of nature in glorifying God—both unintentionally and willfully sinning against the Lord. Finally, in verse 14, he says, &lt;q&gt;May these words of my mouth and this meditation of my heart be pleasing in your sight, Lord, my Rock and my Redeemer.&lt;/q&gt; David knows that he cannot earn God’s favor, but he appeals to God’s graciousness in his relationship with his creator. Though I am a sinner, may the words I speak and the reflections of my heart demonstrate a deep love for God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;until-jesus-returns-the-bible-is-our-supreme-source-of-special-revelation&quot;&gt;“Until Jesus returns, the Bible is our supreme source of special revelation”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;16&lt;/sup&gt; For we did not follow cleverly devised stories when we told you about the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ in power, but we were eyewitnesses of his majesty. &lt;sup&gt;17&lt;/sup&gt; He received honor and glory from God the Father when the voice came to him from the Majestic Glory, saying, &lt;q&gt;This is my Son, whom I love; with him I am well pleased.&lt;/q&gt; &lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt; We ourselves heard this voice that came from heaven when we were with him on the sacred mountain. &lt;sup&gt;19&lt;/sup&gt; We also have the prophetic message as something completely reliable, and you will do well to pay attention to it, as to a light shining in a dark place, until the day dawns and the morning star rises in your hearts. &lt;sup&gt;20&lt;/sup&gt; Above all, you must understand that no prophecy of Scripture came about by the prophet’s own interpretation of things. &lt;sup&gt;21&lt;/sup&gt; For prophecy never had its origin in the human will, but prophets, though human, spoke from God as they were carried along by the Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Peter 1:16–21, NIV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bible is God’s inspired word, and Dr. Swain points to this passage from the apostle Peter’s second letter as the best declaration in Scripture of the Bible’s own inspiration. He notes two things that this passage teaches us. (There are actually more than two.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that this passage teaches is that prophets and apostles had &lt;q&gt;special access&lt;/q&gt; to God’s revelations. They did not simply interpret events happening around them as being related in some way to God, filling in the gaps of their observations with contrivances. Secondly, each prophet and apostle had a special anointing from the Holy Spirit, allowing them to remember what they saw and &lt;q&gt;reliably communicate it to us.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This passage also affirms the unity of Scripture. What the prophets foretold, the apostles witnessed. As Swain notes toward the end of his lecture, &lt;q&gt;All of Scripture holds together as a testimony to Christ.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bible is inspired. It’s unified. And it’s sufficient. Earlier in the chapter, Peter writes, &lt;q&gt;His divine power has given us everything we need for a godly life &lt;strong&gt;through our knowledge of him&lt;/strong&gt; who called us by his own glory and goodness&lt;/q&gt; (v. 3, emphasis added). In addition, Scripture is reliable and authoritative (v. 19). It’s also clear. The Bible is not always clear, as Peter himself acknowledges later in this letter&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but the basic message of Scripture is clear: God desires for humanity to know him and share in his rest, and his love for us is so great that he redeemed us for union with himself forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott Swain’s final point looks to the second half of verse 19: &lt;q&gt;…as to a light shining in a dark place, until the day dawns and the morning star rises in your hearts.&lt;/q&gt; Scripture is our supreme source of special revelation &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;—until the second advent of Christ. As we await with eagerness &lt;q&gt;the blessed hope—the appearing of the glory of our great God and Savior, Jesus Christ&lt;/q&gt; (Titus 2:13, NIV), we have at present &lt;q&gt;a lamp for [our] feet, a light on [our] path&lt;/q&gt; (Psalm 119:105, NIV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bible is inspired, unified, sufficient, reliable, authoritative, and clear. Scripture is &lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt; God, &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; God, and leads us &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; God, where we &lt;q&gt;will find rest for [our] souls&lt;/q&gt; (Matthew 11:29). Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There are certainly matters of even lower importance. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;For I delivered to you as of first importance what I also received: that Christ died for our sins in accordance with the Scriptures, that he was buried, that he was raised on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures, and that he appeared to Cephas, then to the twelve.&lt;/q&gt; (1 Corinthians 15:3–5, ESV) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Speaking of Paul, Peter writes, &lt;q&gt;His letters contain some things that are hard to understand.&lt;/q&gt; (2 Peter 3:16, NIV) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="systematic theology" /><category term="Scripture" /><summary type="html">This article represents my collection of notes and personal thoughts on the “Basics of Systematic Theology: Scripture” lecture by Scott R. Swain, Ph.D. at Reformed Theological Seminary in 2017. All unattributed quotations are those of Dr. Swain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Waiting and hoping</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/waiting-hoping" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Waiting and hoping" /><published>2022-12-04T06:59:01-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T06:59:01-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/waiting-hoping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/waiting-hoping">&lt;p&gt;It is sometimes difficult to know the difference between God speaking and my own thoughts. But when God interrupts me, it’s obvious. That’s what happened in the middle of corporate worship on a Sunday morning in July. I experienced the Holy Spirit comforting me in the midst of anxiety, self-doubt, and impatience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling was the same as what I felt five years ago when I learned that my first child had died in the womb: despair, longing, and hope. Upon hearing confirmation of my son’s stillbirth, I was overcome by a strange and conflicting sense of sadness and hope—hope that I would yet know the joy of the Lord. And I did. I learned a great deal about joy in the midst of sorrow, pain, and longing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;losing-ezra-james&quot;&gt;Losing Ezra James&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That September day in 2017, as I paced the hospital room, waiting and hoping for a miracle for my unborn child, all I could do was pray. After more than two hours and several medical tests, my wife’s doctor walked in and confirmed the worst: there was no heartbeat; my son was gone. In the moments following, my mind briefly ran to panic, then immediately to sadness. Within a second or two of realizing that my son was dead, I heard a song playing in my head—frustratingly in the front of my grief-stricken mind. It was the song &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyIGnuDwBKA&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Joy of the Lord&lt;/em&gt;, by Twila Paris&lt;/a&gt;, which we sang in my church growing up. It was the most perplexing song to hear at that moment, and I hated myself at the time for thinking of it. It was only a few hours later that I realized that the Holy Spirit had put that familiar song on my mind at just the right time to remind me that true joy isn’t dependent upon circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joy of the Lord&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;—that peculiar, hope-filled, abiding, content-in-all-circumstances portion—is found in the dark places of our lives, when we come to terms with the reality that there’s no redemption on our own, no reconciling our own past or present or future, no walking out of the darkness ourselves, because it’s Jesus who redeems us, who saves us, is saving us, and will save us, and who carries us out of the darkest moments of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small mercy from the loss of my son, Ezra James Caples, was that he was born perfect—without visible bodily damage. Not every angel&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has the same outcome. We get to treasure beautiful pictures of a baby who looks alive. As I held his lifeless body, I was overwhelmed with feelings of longing, despair, grief, anger. And joy. I kept thinking, &lt;q&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is my son, my child.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/q&gt; I couldn’t keep from smiling at my firstborn. I loved him so much at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our entire church showed up at the funeral, and we sang &lt;em&gt;The Joy of the Lord&lt;/em&gt; among the trees and grave markers in Nashville, Tennessee. It was a hot day for September, and the mosquitoes were hungry. But the biting sense of unfairness stung the most. Why did God give us so much happiness during the pregnancy months, only to take away our only child? Human suffering is a difficult topic and not one I’m attempting to address here, but I’ve learned to trust God and pursue joy in the wake of grief. God has been good to me, and I can’t say much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-funeral.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-funeral.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Graveside funeral service for Ezra James Caples, born sleeping September 9, 2017&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anxiety&quot;&gt;Anxiety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always dealt with social anxiety. I was a shy kid who never spoke up in class unless I was called on. (And being called on in class was terrifying.) I’ve been that way for as long as I can remember. I manage it better now, but I still feel tense around people I don’t know well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pushing-grief-aside&quot;&gt;Pushing grief aside&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February of 2018, I quit my job without another one lined up—uncharacteristic for me. It had only been five months since losing Ezra, but my wife suggested I quit the job I hated in order to take some time to grieve. We had also been doing grief counseling, which really helped me in many ways, one of which was realizing that I had been operating as if I hadn’t just experienced a loss. I had returned to work one week after my son’s stillbirth and, in many ways, acted like I needed to be strong for my wife—without taking time to grieve myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had some pent-up bitterness toward the people around me—my co-workers—for not responding to my grief in the ways that I thought I needed. It felt like none of them even cared about my pain. That was a very unfair burden to place on a group of people who really didn’t know me very well. And even if they had, grief manifests in ways that surprise even the griever. Another lesson from therapy: Most people mean well, but they still don’t know how to respond to someone else’s grief. I’ve found this is doubly true when people don’t know how to categorize a loss—like stillbirth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-fears&quot;&gt;Health fears&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that month, I came down with a virus of some kind. I remember lying on the couch, struggling to breathe and seriously wondering if I would suffocate. We drove to the hospital, where I spent the next three days recovering from myocarditis, a condition marked by inflammation of the heart muscle. The viral infection had triggered an immune response in my heart. Though my heart wouldn’t give me any more real trouble after that (so far), I couldn’t shake the anxiety that had weaponized my diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward to 2020: The COVID-19 pandemic has been hard on everyone, in many different ways. 6.6 million deaths worldwide&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, countless medical after-effects, relationships forever lost, abuse of all kinds on the rise, anxiety and depression skyrocketing. The toll is much larger than statistics can bear. And I was afraid for much of the pandemic—for my health, for my wife and living child&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and for my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last few years struggling with anxiety about my heart health, my family’s health, my job, the global pandemic, and other concerns. Anxiety can be hard to shake. It’s not logical, and you can’t reason your way out of it—at least I haven’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jesus-friend-of-the-anxious&quot;&gt;Jesus, friend of the anxious&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of silence from God—or more likely, closed ears on my part—he spoke to me in an elementary school gym as the congregation sang. But it wasn’t words that were communicated, only a feeling of comfort, as if El Roi, &lt;em&gt;the God who sees&lt;/em&gt;, were wrapping me in his arms and whispering, &lt;q&gt;I’ve got you.&lt;/q&gt; It was simple and not particularly profound, but I couldn’t hold back my tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sermon that day was on Psalm 25, an acrostic poem by David. In this psalm, David appeals multiple times to God to save him from his sins and his enemies. As in many of his psalms, David seems very anxious, recognizing the very real dangers of both his sinfulness and the malice of his enemies. Three times he mentions waiting for Yahweh (vv. 3, 5, 21). The transliterated word for &lt;q&gt;wait&lt;/q&gt; here is &lt;em&gt;qavah&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span dir=&quot;rtl&quot;&gt;קָוָה&lt;/span&gt;), which connotes both waiting and hoping. But the hope is not simply &lt;em&gt;wishing for something to happen&lt;/em&gt;; it’s waiting &lt;em&gt;in expectation that it will happen&lt;/em&gt;. David’s hope in the Lord is an expectation of his salvation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it’s the same with anxiety. I’m waiting on the Lord and hoping in his promise of deliverance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Turn to me and be gracious to me,&lt;br /&gt;
for I am alone and afflicted.&lt;br /&gt;
The distresses of my heart increase;&lt;br /&gt;
bring me out of my sufferings.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Psalm 25:16–17, CSB&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-worry&quot;&gt;“Don’t worry”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up believing that anxiety is sinful, but I don’t think it’s that simple. In Matthew 6, Jesus teaches us not to worry (&lt;q&gt;be anxious&lt;/q&gt;) about our lives (vv. 25–34), but I think this is more a comfort than a command. Consider how he illustrates the Father’s care for the birds (v. 26) and the wildflowers (vv. 28–30). Our heavenly Father knows our needs (v. 32), and he provides for his creation—the same creation over which humanity has dominion (Genesis 1:26). How much more, then, will he provide for his beloved children? Jesus offers comfort to those afflicted with anxiety, worry, and fear. &lt;q&gt;Therefore don’t worry about tomorrow, because tomorrow will worry about itself. Each day has enough trouble of its own.&lt;/q&gt; (v. 34) Truly, his &lt;q&gt;yoke is easy and [his] burden is light.&lt;/q&gt; (Matthew 11:30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew 6:25–34 is directly linked to the preceding verses (19–24). This passage isn’t just about greed and material wealth. When we fix our eyes on anything but Jesus, our &lt;q&gt;treasure in heaven,&lt;/q&gt; the instability of those things will inevitably lead us into anxiety. For our eyes to be healthy, we must look to the Light, not gaze into the darkness and wonder about the security of our health, beauty, intelligence, wealth, relationships, and abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who say, &lt;q&gt;Jesus never had anxiety&lt;/q&gt; have not closely read Luke 22, when Jesus sweated blood while praying &lt;q&gt;in anguish&lt;/q&gt; in the Garden of Gethsemane&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (vv. 39–46&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). Sweating blood is actually a very rare condition called hematidrosis that can be caused by intense stress. Jesus, knowing his destiny, was very anxious about going to the cross. He understands our anxieties and fears. &lt;q&gt;Therefore, let us approach the throne of grace with boldness, so that we may receive mercy and find grace to help us in time of need.&lt;/q&gt; (Hebrews 4:16, CSB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could argue that being under intense stress for a few hours is not the same as prolonged anxiety—it’s not—but Jesus experiencing anxiety, even briefly, is enough to establish that, not only is anxiety not sinful, it’s also common. I hope we can find some comfort in that. Jesus, being &lt;q&gt;without sin,&lt;/q&gt; (Hebrews 4:15)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; could not have experienced anxiety if it were a sin to do so. More than that, he understands our struggles with anxiety. Your fears and worries are not sinful, but Jesus still calls us away from the yoke of anxiety. I choose to believe it’s possible, even if incredibly difficult, to unburden ourselves from chronic worry, stress, anxiety, and fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not there yet, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-to-listenand-talk&quot;&gt;Learning to listen—and talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After moving away from the community that loved us well, at quite possibly the worst time to relocate—December of 2019—I’ve spent the last three years disconnected. I’ve realized that I’m not quite as introverted as I thought, and I need to listen to my own longing for connectivity. I work from home in a quiet suburban neighborhood, doing mostly solo work, in a city where I still know very few people. It can be lonely, which is why I’m once again pursuing therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, my anxiety is much less of a burden—for now. (Thank you, Wonderful Counselor!) I’m not a mental health expert by any means, and I don’t intend to suggest that prayer is a guaranteed prescription for anxiety. It’s not. But prayer is a crucial component in my personal anxiety journey, along with therapy&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and attention to my personal and interpersonal needs. Daily prayer, good nutrition, regular exercise, keeping caffeine in check, professional counseling, social presence, recreation. These are all ways that I’ve found to meaningfully cope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My social anxiety is not gone, though some of my other worries are. And I still miss Ezra; I hung his ornament on our Christmas tree yesterday. There are fewer triggers for my grief now, but the holidays can still be heavy. Christmas is joyful, fun, and spiritual, but the season still reminds me that I have two children, and only one of them can eat his gingerbread house face-first, hum Christmas music while decorating the tree, and cuddle up to holiday cartoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I feel more hopeful than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-ornament.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-ornament.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;mb-12 shadow&quot; alt=&quot;A polar bear ornament with the name Ezra written on it, hanging on a Christmas tree&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-grave-marker-brother.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/faith/ezra-grave-marker-brother.jpeg&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Ezra&apos;s 3-year old brother standing beside his grave marker&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;Nehemiah said, &lt;q&gt;Go and enjoy choice food and sweet drinks, and send some to those who have nothing prepared. This day is holy to our Lord. Do not grieve, for &lt;strong&gt;the joy of the Lord is your strength&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/q&gt; (Nehemiah 8:10, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“Angel” is the term used for babies lost during or immediately after pregnancy. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Source: World Health Organization. https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019. Accessed 4 December 2022. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Our second child, also a boy, was born almost two years after Ezra, in July of 2019. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The garden was at the base of the Mount of Olives, part of a Judean mountain range separating Jerusalem from the wilderness. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This story is also found in Matthew 26:36–45 and Mark 14:32–42, and it’s referenced in John 18:1. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See also Romans 5:12, 8:3; 2 Corinthians 5:21; Hebrews 7:26, 9:14; 1 Peter 1:19, 2:22; 1 John 3:5. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As of December 2022, I’m trying to get an appointment with a therapist in a non-virtual session who will accept my insurance. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="anxiety" /><category term="grief" /><summary type="html">It is sometimes difficult to know the difference between God speaking and my own thoughts. But when God interrupts me, it’s obvious. That’s what happened in the middle of corporate worship on a Sunday morning in July. I experienced the Holy Spirit comforting me in the midst of anxiety, self-doubt, and impatience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to create a Google account without Gmail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to create a Google account without Gmail" /><published>2022-11-03T09:14:59-04:00</published><updated>2022-11-03T09:14:59-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/how-to-create-a-google-account-without-gmail">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you can have a Google account without a Gmail address? With so many products and services, millions of people use Google. But what if you like your existing email address? You can create a Google account without Gmail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially useful when using Google’s business services, like Search Console, Google Ads, Google Analytics, etc. It’s a really nice way to compartmentalize your personal and work accounts and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Google services, like Google Ads, allow administrators to restrict users to those with specific email domains, such as those of your business. For Ads, this is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/google-ads/answer/2375456?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;font-bold&quot;&gt;Allowed Domains&lt;/a&gt;. But you must also have a Google account to use these products, which is exactly how I ended up creating my new non-Gmail account this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://accounts.google.com/SignUpWithoutGmail&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accounts.google.com/SignUpWithoutGmail&lt;/a&gt; to get started. Fill out the form (pictured below) using the email address that you want to use when signing into your new Google account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture class=&quot;block md:mx-12 xl:mx-0&quot;&gt;
	&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/img/martech/create-your-google-account.webp&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/martech/create-your-google-account.png&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; alt=&quot;Create your Google account without Gmail&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking &lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;, update your new account with additional information, like your gender and birthdate. Next, verify that you’re human by completing the CAPTCHA. Agree to Google’s Terms of Service and Privacy Policy by checking the corresponding box. Now click &lt;strong&gt;Next step&lt;/strong&gt; to submit the form and create your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your Google account created, you will now need to confirm that you own the email address provided. Go to your email inbox and look for an email from Google. Click the link inside to confirm your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can sign into your new Google account, and the email address username is your non-Gmail address!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="Google" /><summary type="html">Did you know that you can have a Google account without a Gmail address? With so many products and services, millions of people use Google. But what if you like your existing email address? You can create a Google account without Gmail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remove .DS_Store with Git</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remove .DS_Store with Git" /><published>2022-06-26T00:14:39-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-26T00:14:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/martech/2022/git-remove-ds-store">&lt;p&gt;Every developer with a Mac computer has encountered the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; file in their Git code. If you don’t know what it is, this file could be alarming. Don’t worry; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; is harmless. But it can be annoying when it shows up in every folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-ds_store-file&quot;&gt;What is the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; file?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; is a hidden metadata file exclusive to Mac computers, though you could possibly come across it on a Windows PC that is sharing project code with a Mac. The file simply contains information specific to the folder it’s in: folder color, icon size, window size, file order, etc. The file is created the first time you select any View Options for a folder, but it’s hidden using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; prefix. However, you can see it in the terminal using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; command. And of course, it also shows up in Git repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-remove-ds_store-files-from-a-git-repository&quot;&gt;How to remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files from a Git repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove (and prevent) &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from your project code, I recommend first checking out a new branch with the following command: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git checkout -b [BRANCH-NAME]&lt;/code&gt;. Then make sure you’re in the root of your project folder so that your changes will affect the whole project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remove-ds_store&quot;&gt;Remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the following terminal command to find all previously committed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files and remove them from your project. If &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git rm&lt;/code&gt; makes you uneasy, you can perform a dry run to check the files that would be removed, without actually removing anything. To do this, add either &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--dry-run&lt;/code&gt; as a flag following &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rm&lt;/code&gt;, like this: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;... git rm -n --ignore-unmatch&lt;/code&gt;. Once you’ve seen what will be removed, repeat the full command without the flag to remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-console&quot; data-lang=&quot;console&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;go&quot;&gt;find . -name .DS_Store -print0 | xargs -0 git rm --ignore-unmatch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;add-to-gitignore&quot;&gt;Add to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; from entering your project’s code again, add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**/.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file. If it does not exist, create the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of your project folder and add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**/.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; on its own line. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; part of the command tells Git that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files should be ignored in every folder of your project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commit-changes&quot;&gt;Commit changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commit your changes and push them to your remote repository. If you review the changes made in your version control host, you’ll notice that the updates remove all the instances of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt;, along with adding that line to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="MarTech" /><category term="web development" /><category term="Git" /><summary type="html">Every developer with a Mac computer has encountered the .DS_Store file in their Git code. If you don’t know what it is, this file could be alarming. Don’t worry; .DS_Store is harmless. But it can be annoying when it shows up in every folder.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is eternal life: know your God</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is eternal life: know your God" /><published>2022-05-26T12:39:31-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-26T12:39:31-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/this-is-eternal-life">&lt;p&gt;“Is this real life?” &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/txqiwrbYGrs&quot;&gt;David After Dentist&lt;/a&gt; is a hilarious viral video of a 7-year old boy fresh out of a dental procedure who is clearly still feeling the effects of nitrous oxide, or laughing gas. David’s father assures him that, yes, this is real life. But for Christians, this is also eternal life. We’re living in it now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eternal-life-is-knowing-god&quot;&gt;Eternal life is knowing God&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In John 17, Jesus defines eternal life as knowing God:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; Jesus spoke these things, looked up to heaven, and said, “Father, the hour has come. Glorify your Son so that the Son may glorify you, &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; since you gave him authority over all people, so that he may give eternal life to everyone you have given him. &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; This is eternal life: that they may know you, the only true God, and the one you have sent—Jesus Christ. &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; I have glorified you on the earth by completing the work you gave me to do. &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt; Now, Father, glorify me in your presence with that glory I had with you before the world existed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;John 17:1–5, &lt;abbr title=&quot;Christian Standard Bible&quot;&gt;CSB&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This passage is the beginning of the longest recorded prayer of Jesus, and it’s filled with love for his disciples—all of us throughout history. As Gary M. Burge notes, &lt;q&gt;John 17 gives us a glimpse into the heart of Jesus unlike any other chapter in the four Gospels.&lt;/q&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The NIV Application Commentary: John&lt;/em&gt;) Dane Ortlund takes it further in his book, &lt;a href=&quot;/book-reviews/gentle-and-lowly&quot; class=&quot;italic&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gentle and Lowly&lt;/a&gt;, when he describes Christ’s bottomless well of grace: &lt;q&gt;Jesus Christ is comforted when you draw from the riches of his atoning work, because his own body is getting healed.&lt;/q&gt; Jesus desires for his people to not only be with him eternally, but to come to him now, in this age, for grace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack in just these five verses, but one phrase that is often overlooked is, “This is eternal life: that they may know you” (v. 3). Louis Berkhof describes the nature of eternal life in his major theological treatise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The reward of the righteous is described as eternal life, that is, not merely an endless life, but life in all its fulness, without any of the imperfections and disturbances of the present, Matt. 25:46; Rom. 2:7. The fulness of this life is enjoyed in communion with God, which is really the essence of eternal life, Rev. 21:3. They will see God in Jesus Christ face to face, will find full satisfaction in Him, will rejoice in Him, and will glorify Him.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Louis Berkhof, Systematic Theology&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eternal life is not simply living forever, nor does it begin once the faithful believer dies. The gift of eternal life is complete and everlasting union with the fullness of God in Jesus Christ, face to face. Even better, it begins in this life. If eternal life, as defined by Christ himself, is to know God, then those of us who know God are experiencing it now. Eternal life for the Christian bleeds backward into time. Just as a door can be opened to let in the sunshine while a person is still inside, so too, can the Christian experience the warmth of the Son in this present life. And how much better to finally pass through that open door into the fresh air of God’s full glory? (Philippians 1:12)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;obstacles-to-experiencing-eternal-life-now&quot;&gt;Obstacles to experiencing eternal life now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many obstacles to experiencing the warmth of Jesus in this present life. To continue with the open door analogy, there’s a lot happening in this room. Life gets busy and distracting. Our bodies and minds are imperfect, plaguing us with physical and mental sicknesses. Anxiety, depression, cancer, eating disorders, insomnia. Evil abounds, striving always to turn our eyes and hearts away from Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These “imperfections and disturbances,” as Berkhof calls them, can be seriously heavy burdens. It would be dismissive to suggest that the person struggling with depression simply have more faith, though. God chooses to work primarily through his creation, and we’re not meant to live the Christian life alone. &lt;q cite=&quot;Galatians 6:2, CSB&quot;&gt;Carry one another’s burdens,&lt;/q&gt; (Galatians 6:2, CSB) and allow others to carry yours. Seek professional help, if needed, to manage the things that might prevent you from experiencing the Son of God presently. &lt;strong&gt;It is not a weak faith that treats &lt;em&gt;fill-in-the-blank&lt;/em&gt; with health providers, prescribed medication, or licensed therapists.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;look-to-the-second-coming&quot;&gt;Look to the second coming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Christians, our hope is found in Jesus and his second coming to restore all things to perfection. We are told to watch and pray in anticipation of the second coming of Christ, &lt;q cite=&quot;Jude 21, CSB&quot;&gt;waiting expectantly for the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ for eternal life.&lt;/q&gt; (Jude 21, CSB)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="eternal life" /><category term="eschatology" /><category term="gospels" /><summary type="html">“Is this real life?” David After Dentist is a hilarious viral video of a 7-year old boy fresh out of a dental procedure who is clearly still feeling the effects of nitrous oxide, or laughing gas. David’s father assures him that, yes, this is real life. But for Christians, this is also eternal life. We’re living in it now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Christ in you, the hope of glory</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/christ-in-you-hope-of-glory" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Christ in you, the hope of glory" /><published>2022-05-20T13:00:01-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-20T13:00:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/christ-in-you-hope-of-glory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faith/2022/christ-in-you-hope-of-glory">&lt;p&gt;Is there a Christian teacher whom you greatly respect but have never met? How would it feel to receive a personal letter from that person commending you for your faith and revealing their prayers for you? That is how the church in Colossae must have felt to receive a letter from the apostle Paul. By the time he wrote Colossians, Paul was well-known in the growing Christian movement, and Colossae was a small city with little influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul did not plant the Colossian church; he likely never even visited it. But he had heard about their “faith in Christ Jesus and of the love you have for all the saints” (1:4) through Epaphras. Epaphras is probably the one who started the Colossian church, and the minister of Christ who “told us about your love in the Spirit.” (1:8)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The letter to the Colossians is rich with theology. N. T. Wright notes, &lt;q&gt;Faced with a young church in a small town in up-country Asia Minor, Paul has written a letter in which he has distilled his understanding of some of the greatest themes in theology.&lt;/q&gt; (Wright, 40)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; There’s so much to discuss in Colossians, but Paul’s brief mention of ministering to the church in 1:24–29 can be a particularly tricky passage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt; Now I rejoice in my sufferings for your sake, and in my flesh I am filling up what is lacking in Christ’s afflictions for the sake of his body, that is, the church, &lt;sup&gt;25&lt;/sup&gt; of which I became a minister according to the stewardship from God that was given to me for you, to make the word of God fully known, &lt;sup&gt;26&lt;/sup&gt; the mystery hidden for ages and generations but now revealed to his saints. &lt;sup&gt;27&lt;/sup&gt; To them God chose to make known how great among the Gentiles are the riches of the glory of this mystery, which is Christ in you, the hope of glory. &lt;sup&gt;28&lt;/sup&gt; Him we proclaim, warning everyone and teaching everyone with all wisdom, that we may present everyone mature in Christ. &lt;sup&gt;29&lt;/sup&gt; For this I toil, struggling with all his energy that he powerfully works within me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Colossians 1:24–29, &lt;abbr title=&quot;English Standard Version&quot;&gt;ESV&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rejoicing-in-sufferings&quot;&gt;Rejoicing in sufferings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul begins this passage by rejoicing in his sufferings &lt;q&gt;for your [the church’s] sake&lt;/q&gt; (v. 24) He rejoices in his sufferings elsewhere in his writings&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, so this is not strange. Paul understands that he must suffer (Acts 9:16) along with all Christians, but Wright believes Paul to be &lt;q&gt;drawing the enemy’s fire on to himself&lt;/q&gt; (p. 89) as a way to relieve the young Colossian church of excess affliction. Personally, I see the clause “for your sake” as qualifying the rejoicing, not the suffering. Students of Greek grammar can correct me if I’m wrong, but I might re-write it this way: &lt;q&gt;Now I rejoice, for your sake, in my sufferings…&lt;/q&gt; With this rendering, Paul would be modeling joy in suffering for a young church already struggling with how to live as Christians. I have to admit, though, both interpretations seem very reasonable to me and align with Paul’s character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-paul-provide-what-is-lacking-in-christs-afflictions&quot;&gt;Does Paul provide what is lacking in Christ’s afflictions?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of verse 24 is strange and difficult:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;q&gt;… and in my flesh I am filling up what is lacking in Christ’s afflictions for the sake of his body, that is, the church…&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could be lacking in Christ’s afflictions? Is Paul suggesting that the atonement on the cross is somehow incomplete? &lt;em&gt;I have to admit that I don’t clearly understand Paul’s meaning here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard the interpretation that what’s lacking is gospel preaching—that since Jesus is no longer on the earth, Paul is picking up his preaching where he left off. This exposition seems incomplete to me. It’s true that Jesus is no longer physically preaching to people, but that doesn’t seem to create “lack” in Christ’s afflictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I fall more in line with how N. T. Wright and others interpret this passage. The church will necessarily suffer as Christ himself suffered. What is lacking in Christ’s afflictions is continued suffering. Christ no longer endures trials, temptations, and abuse in this world; his suffering has ended. But our suffering—the trials of believers around the world and through the ages—continues, and Paul &lt;q&gt;is filling up&lt;/q&gt; whatever contains all the Christian suffering, by enduring an excess amount, yet joyfully. This interpretation aligns well with Wright’s explanation for Paul’s suffering in the first half of verse 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mystery&quot;&gt;The mystery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1:25–27, Paul next refers to himself as a minister to the church—both the larger body of Christ and the Colossian church, which likely was mostly Gentile converts. In verse 25, he mentions his stewardship from God &lt;q&gt;to make the word of God fully known&lt;/q&gt; and calls it &lt;q&gt;the mystery hidden for ages and generations&lt;/q&gt; (ESV). These verses are strikingly similar to part of Paul’s letter to the church in Ephesus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt; Of this gospel I was made a minister according to the gift of God’s grace, which was given me by the working of his power. &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt; To me, though I am the very least of all the saints, this grace was given, to preach to the Gentiles the unsearchable riches of Christ, &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; and to bring to light for everyone what is the plan of the mystery hidden for ages in God, who created all things, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt; so that through the church the manifold wisdom of God might now be made known to the rulers and authorities in the heavenly places.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ephesians 3:7–10, ESV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In both passages, Paul states that he was made a minister to the church by God for the sake of the Gentiles, he mentions the riches of Christ, and he proclaims the &lt;q&gt;mystery hidden for ages&lt;/q&gt; which he has been charged with sharing. The mystery here should not be thought of by the English definition of a mystery, as a puzzle or perplexity. N. T. Wright notes, &lt;q&gt;In their looking forward to the day when God would act in history to restore the fortunes of his people, some Jewish seers expressed their hopes in terms of the ‘secret plans’ that God was reserving for the last great day.&lt;/q&gt; The plans of Yahweh are alluded to throughout the Old Testament but are now revealed to all God’s people. These plans are not a timeline of events, however, but a person: Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;christ-in-you-the-hope-of-glory&quot;&gt;&lt;q&gt;Christ in you, the hope of glory&lt;/q&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Christology of Colossians 1:15–20 is amplified in the words, &lt;q&gt;Christ in you, the hope of glory&lt;/q&gt; (v. 27) Paul expands on this ancient mystery which is revealed to the Gentiles (not just the people of Israel!): Messiah (Christ) lives in/among you (plural), which is your hope of future glory.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Of the “riches” of verse 27, Wright notes, &lt;q&gt;Among these treasures is the fact that God’s glory is to be &lt;em&gt;shared&lt;/em&gt; with his people (&lt;em&gt;cf.&lt;/em&gt; Rom. 5:2). This &lt;em&gt;hope of glory&lt;/em&gt; is a certainty because of the mystery itself, which is &lt;em&gt;Christ in you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/q&gt; (92) The righteousness of Christ is counted to those who live by faith in him. W. G. T. Shedd writes in his &lt;em&gt;Dogmatic Theology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;q&gt;Christ’s perfect obedience which merits eternal life is not the sinner’s perfect obedience, but God imputes it to him: he calls or reckons it his.&lt;/q&gt; (Shedd, 700)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paul-works-because-god-works&quot;&gt;Paul works because God works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final two verses of this short passage, Paul presents the reason for his labors, &lt;q&gt;that we may present everyone mature in Christ&lt;/q&gt; (v. 28) With this statement, Paul reflects Christ himself. As verse 22 reveals, reconciliation between God and humanity was achieved by Jesus by his death on the cross, &lt;q&gt;in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach.&lt;/q&gt; In other words, Christ reconciled us to God by imputing his righteousness to us &lt;em&gt;so that&lt;/em&gt; we may stand before God “holy and blameless and above reproach.” Paul labors steadfastly; God is at work and so he must be as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul ends the first chapter of Colossians&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on a high note: he gives all his energy—and truly it’s actually Christ’s energy imparted to Paul (&lt;q&gt;that he powerfully works within me&lt;/q&gt;)—to the stewardship he’s been given by God to proclaim the gospel to the Gentiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key message of these verses, I think, is that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is capable of Christian maturity in Christ—both Jew and Gentile. I’ll close with a quote from Wright’s commentary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Then it is that the goal of maturity (not ‘perfection’ in the sense of sinlessness, as Phil. 3:13–14 makes clear) may be in sight. This goal is possible &lt;q&gt;in Christ&lt;/q&gt;: the Image of God himself now lives in his people by his Spirit (1:8), working secretly until their life and his are indistinguishable in their basic character, in true humanity (1:27; 3:10).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;N. T. Wright, “The Epistles of Paul to the Colossians and to Philemon: An Introduction and Commentary” (p. 94)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Wright, N. T. &lt;em&gt;The Epistles of Paul to the Colossians and to Philemon: An Introduction and Commentary&lt;/em&gt;, Inter-Varsity Press, Leicester, England, 1986. Tyndale New Testament Commentaries. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Cf. Romans 5:3–5; 2 Corinthians 12:10; Philippians 1:12–18, 3:10–11. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;See also, &lt;q&gt;we declare God’s wisdom, a mystery that has been hidden and that God destined for our glory before time began.&lt;/q&gt; (1 Corinthians 2:7, &lt;abbr title=&quot;New International Version&quot;&gt;NIV&lt;/abbr&gt;) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Shedd, W. G. T. (1888). &lt;em&gt;Dogmatic Theology&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In actuality, Paul’s letter contained no chapters or verses, and chapter 2 continues with his labor for the church and the mystery of Christ. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;It’s not insignificant that Paul uses the word &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; three times in verse 28. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Caples</name></author><category term="Faith" /><category term="Christ" /><category term="Paul&apos;s letters" /><summary type="html">Is there a Christian teacher whom you greatly respect but have never met? How would it feel to receive a personal letter from that person commending you for your faith and revealing their prayers for you? That is how the church in Colossae must have felt to receive a letter from the apostle Paul. By the time he wrote Colossians, Paul was well-known in the growing Christian movement, and Colossae was a small city with little influence.</summary></entry></feed>